<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Engineer, Consultant, BI Developer in MarTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys With PuTTY and Cygwin for Windows</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY: a free SSH and Telnet client&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY: a free SSH and Telnet client&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;, I need to login to a number of client-specific Linux machines via a terminal emulator (there is no UI for these remote environments) from my local Windows laptop. For this my team uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cygwin.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cygwin&lt;/a&gt;, a Linux-like environment for Windows making it possible to port software running on POSIX systems (such as Linux, BSD, and Unix systems) to Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to login of course just using a standard username/password combination with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mosh.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mosh&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Shell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt; at the command line. However, the more secure (and easier to manage) approach is to utilize SSH keys to login into a virtual private server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my computer to use public/private SSH key pairings for accessing different environments. I previously &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about using SSH keys with Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows. While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to use the same SSH key pairings that were used for that, I prefer the more secure approach of generating specific pairings for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/github.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gitlab&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/gitlab.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and any client-specific instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the following PuTTY files from this site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&#34;&gt;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuTTY (the SSH and Telnet client itself)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pageant (an SSH authentication agent for PuTTY, PSCP, PSFTP, and Plink)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuTTYgen (an RSA and DSA key generation utility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the downloaded PuTTYgen executable, &lt;a href=&#34;https://winscp.net/eng/docs/ui_puttygen#generating_a_new_key&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;generate a new key&lt;/a&gt;. Click the &amp;lsquo;Save public key&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Save private key&amp;rsquo; buttons to save these to the same location as your other keys (the .ssh folder of your home directory, C:\Users\&lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;\.ssh). When saving the private key you will be optionally asked to enter a password for another layer of security if desired - it is also possible to hit &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; and not use a password in combination with the SSH private key. Keep PuTTYgen open for now as you will need to copy the public key value into the authorized_keys files on the appropriate private server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty_gen.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3:f77569a6b4afc10750083404d55c7c58&#34;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up Cygwin and log into the machine that you wish to configure with SSH keys. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the standard username/password credentials for the instance for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Ultimate Python Programming Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/python.png&#34; alt=&#34;Python&#34; title=&#34;Python&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/the-ultimate-python-programming-course&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COURSE LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-H1VZZXZV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COMPLETION CERTIFICATE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Python more for work and took this course to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of the language. Previously, I had been wanting to add Python to my personal tech stack for some time as it is a powerful (and popular) all-purpose programming language. It is a high-level language, meaning it looks more like a readable, human language than a low-level language does. The user-friendly syntax makes it one of the easy languages to learn and it is also one of the most commonly-used languages for analytics, data mining, and data science.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;course-progress:b609afaabbef53e4f3d69f90af30ad86&#34;&gt;Course Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 7/18/16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/udemy-ultimate-python&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH With Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/git_windows.png&#34; alt=&#34;Git for Windows&#34; title=&#34;Git for Windows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever written code of any kind for professional and personal purposes, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely come across the concept of Source Control Management (SCM). When I first became a developer, I used Subversion as my SCM tool but have since switched to the more popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. I use git to commit the latest versions of code in both Linux and Windows environments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on Windows in this post as this is the operating system for my personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git itself is strictly a command-line tool and in setting up my Windows machine, I wanted the ability to make passwordless commits via bash commands or through my favorite git GUI tool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt;. Why passwordless? It&amp;rsquo;s gets quite annoying having to enter your Github credentials every single time you push repository changes. Through the use of SSH keys, there is a secure way of doing this that allows Git Bash (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cygwin.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cygwin&lt;/a&gt;) and TortoiseGit to play nice together. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find any good current documentation for this and had to mess around a bit to get the setup I now use, hence the reason for this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the latest version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download/win&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt; and install it. I would recommend you use most of the default settings, including running Git from the Windows Command Prompt so you can use Cygwin as your command-line tool if you prefer it over Git Bash, which comes with this download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/installing_git.png&#34; alt=&#34;Installing Git&#34; title=&#34;Installing Git&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the latest version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://tortoisegit.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt; and install it. There are no special steps to follow here, just keep hitting &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generate an SSH key for your Github account following these &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/generating-an-ssh-key&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;. At the end, be sure to test your SSH connection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ ssh -T git@github.com
# Attempts to ssh to GitHub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did everything correctly here, two files should now exist in a .ssh folder of your home directory (for Windows this will be C:\Users\&lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;\.ssh). By the default they will be named id_rsa (the private SSH key) and id_rsa.pub (the public SSH key). If you have Microsoft Publisher installed on your computer, it will think the public key is a publisher file (because of the .pub extension). Use &amp;lsquo;open with&amp;rsquo; to view this key in a text editor tool like &lt;a href=&#34;https://notepad-plus-plus.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TortoiseGit uses a PuTTY private key file format, so you will need to generate a private key in this format using the private key you generated following the steps from Github. Search your programs and files for PuTTygen, which should have been installed with TortoiseGit. Open this program and go to Conversions &amp;gt; Import key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse to the private key file you generated via &lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen&lt;/code&gt; (see step 4) and import this into PuTTygen. Click the &amp;lsquo;Save private key&amp;rsquo; button after you have imported your private SSH key to save it in PuTTY private key file format (.ppk). You will want to save it to the same location as your other keys (the .ssh folder of your home directory, C:\Users\&lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;\.ssh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/putty_gen.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; title=&#34;PuTTY Key Generator&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/ssh_keys.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;SSH Keys&#34; title=&#34;SSH Keys&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5:ca600a9d3dfcf61b6d7740c7d2519dbe&#34;&gt;Step 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Github repository, select &amp;lsquo;Clone with SSH&amp;rsquo; and copy the URL path to the clipboard (make sure it starts with &lt;code&gt;git@github.com&lt;/code&gt;). Use TortoiseGit to to clone a copy of your Github repository to your local machine (right click in the directory, then select Git Clone&amp;hellip;). Paste the copied URL path into TortoiseGit. Check &amp;lsquo;Load Putty Key&amp;rsquo; and browse to the .ppk file you created in Step 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/tortoisegit_clone.png&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseGit Clone&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseGit Clone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; and that&amp;rsquo;s it! You now have a SSH repository on your Windows machine that you can push passwordless changes with using either the TortoiseGit GUI or the command line with Git Bash (or Cygwin). I tend to use TortoiseGit for one-off commits and automated deployment scripts through the command line for repositories I am frequently making changes to. Regardless of approach, it is nice to have TortoiseGit installed on your Windows machine to easily visually identify any uncommitted changes for a repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/tortoisegit_repo.png&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseGit Repo&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseGit Repo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;andgoss@MYCOMPUTER MINGW64 /C/Github_AG/mssql-library (master)
# Push source and build repos.
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Science Conference East</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com/boston&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/odsc.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; title=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2016 I attended my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Data Science Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Boston. There were some 3,000+ data science practioners that came together at the Boston Convention &amp;amp; Exhibition Center to share ideas about this rapidly changing discipline. The following topics were covered throughout the conference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended sessions on popular data science statistical models and using Python for data science, where we worked through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brianbelljr/fantasy_football/blob/master/football.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop materials from the conference are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opendatascience.com/category/conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;opendatascience.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWSome Day Boston</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/awsome_day.png&#34; alt=&#34;AWSome Day&#34; title=&#34;AWSome Day&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2016 I joined Amazon Web Services for an all-day training event at the Westin Copley Place in Boston. The workshop provided a step-by-step introduction to the core AWS services for compute, storage, database and networking. AWS technical experts explained key features and use cases, shared best practices, and walked through technical demos. We specifically covered the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 1&lt;/b&gt;: AWS Introduction and History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 2&lt;/b&gt;: Infrastructure Services: Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon EBS, and Amazon VPC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 3&lt;/b&gt;: Security, Identity, and Access Management: IAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 4&lt;/b&gt;: Databases: Amazon DynamoDB and Amazon RDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module 5&lt;/b&gt;: AWS Elasticity and Management Tools: Auto Scaling, Elastic Load Balancing, Amazon CloudWatch, and AWS Trusted Advisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was a great for networking, learning more about cloud computing (from the clear market leader in this space) and how to get started on AWS Cloud. It is particularly valuable as some of my working environment is being shifted to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s data warehouse solution, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/redshift&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon Redshift&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides from this event can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/secret/fcDgOrIt5Eldb6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caleb Doxsey- An Introduction to Programming in Go</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/golang_gopher.png&#34; alt=&#34;Golang Gopher&#34; title=&#34;Golang Gopher&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.golang-book.com/books/intro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BOOK LINK&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go (Golang)&lt;/a&gt; is an open source programming language that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software. I first started using Go through my work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;. My department adopted this language as one of our tech stacks for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s open source (i.e. free) and intended to be simple yet expressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s intended to be a good middleware layer to provide for both quick one-off applications as well as large collaborative code bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a static simple language, which allows for static analysis tooling and fast compilation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can easily be compiled across multiple platforms, which is important for us since we host several different commercial and open source operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s based around composition instead of OOP inheritance, which avoids a whole class of issues. There&amp;rsquo;s no type casting hell. Things are either a type or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objects and functionality can easily be combined. Structs provide simple blue-prints. Interfaces provide a lightweight polymorphism without complicating things too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrency is built in through Go routines and channels, which are a simple and efficient means to run multiple executions at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aim in reading this book and completing the accompanying exercises was to gain a thorough understanding on the fundamentals of the Go programming language.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;book-progress:c587c0792512b02996a2b4d2d5abf088&#34;&gt;Book Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 01/27/16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/golang-book&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Programming for Beginners in C#</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/csharp.png&#34; alt=&#34;C#&#34; title=&#34;C#&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/programming-for-complete-beginners-in-csharp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COURSE LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-TT5IFIPW&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COMPLETION CERTIFICATE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on Windows servers throughout my career, which initially got me started with this language. Learning some of the Base Class Library (BCL) of the Microsoft .NET Framework and using these classes through C# has helped me automate various tasks within these environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal in taking this course was to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of C# programming (and objected-oriented programming in general) and to get more practice.
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;course-progress:0419b73c29db8b0a8014c550c35f1f69&#34;&gt;Course Progress&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;progress max=&#34;1.0&#34; value=&#34;1.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/progress&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% - completed 11/28/15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andrewrgoss/udemy-beginning-csharp&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View my code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/hugo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve believed in the importance of having a blog but have struggled to keep one going. I started out using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; back in the day and most recently was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;. But there were features about these blogging platforms that consistently bugged me. Fortunately for me, while I was learning the &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; programming language I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in this language. I started experimenting with Hugo and instantly loved it. I experimented with several different themes and eventually migrated my blog from Wordpress to Hugo. Here are the features I like most about Hugo and how I compare it to Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-previews:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Live Previews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I prepared a post on Wordpress with text and articles I would have to publish it to see how it looks within the context of the overall site. Yes- it&amp;rsquo;s true that you can save content in draft mode and only make it live after proof-reading. But this was in a different screen - the admin section. I much prefer to see a live preview of the full site as I work. When I discovered Hugo and started experimenting with it, I fell in love with the &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; command. This is an inbuilt server that can serve up your website content so you can instantly preview changes as part of the full site the second you save them. There is a way to render drafts too with the &lt;code&gt;--buildDrafts&lt;/code&gt; parameter but I prefer just running the production version knowing that since my site is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, nothing will happen until I commit and push the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;Change detected, rebuilding site
2016-04-25 17:17 -0400
0 draft content
0 future content
10 pages created
13 paginator pages created
9 tags created
in 96 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown-support:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Markdown Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bash script code above is nicely formatted right? The fact that Hugo supports &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; as well as straight-up HTML is another feature I greatly enjoy. For anyone unfamiliar with Markdown, it is a plain text formatting syntax that gets converted to HTML. Using Markdown makes it easier and much quicker to write technical posts as it supports syntax highlighting for a ton of languages. I knew that some of my more technical posts needed to contain code snippets but Wordpress isn&amp;rsquo;t too-friendly for this working in a WYSIWYG editor. Simply copying and pasting this code within a post doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as it removes all of the syntax highlighting and formatting from my favorite IDE (interactive development environment) tools. Yes, there are plugins to support this - but I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable working in Markdown and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to write up content offline if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-hosting-with-github-pages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Free Hosting With Github Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Wordpress I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bluehost.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BlueHost&lt;/a&gt; as my web host, as many do with their Wordpress blogs. It is easy to use and cheap (I was paying $2.99 a month). Moreover, it has lots of features designed specifically for Wordpress usage. The setup was easy enough using a one-click install from the hosting dashboard and then being able to install plugins, themes, and updates, all from the Wordpress admin. But I had to login through that dashboard every time to access my Wordpress site. And while my monthly cost was small, I much prefer free. (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-themes:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Custom Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted a minimalistic, responsive site that is easy to navigate without too much scrolling. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to deny that Hugo has nowhere near the numbers of themes that Wordpress does. On Wordpress I searched through probably hundreds of different themes before settling on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.s5themes.com/theme/focused&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Focused&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo is continuing to add more themes to its library but searching through them was a lot easier since they all live on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo website&lt;/a&gt;. With Wordpress both free and paid themes are scattered across the interwebs. I also found the source code much easier to obtain for the Hugo themes since each one is free and links to its respective Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rendering-speed:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Rendering Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my site rendered very slowly with Wordpress/BlueHost. I’m already a fan and user of the Go language, and so in following a number of the Go social communities, I discovered Hugo. One of the most popular aspects of Go is speed as it is a langauge with subroutines baked in making it easy to execute concurrent processes. The Hugo static site generator is written in Go. A static site generator is an application that can take content in some original description (markdown in the case of Hugo) and render final content by applying rules. This final content can then be hosted anywhere, without the need for server-side runtime support such as Python/PHP/Go/Node/etc. This is because it does not require server-side processing to handle rendering pages on the fly. This makes the site very portable and simple to deploy and can be served out of aggressive caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major disadvantages of Hugo, or any static site generator for that matter, is integrating search. You either need some &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-are-you-implementing-site-search/986/14&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JavaScript magic&lt;/a&gt; or a 3rd party search provider like &lt;a href=&#34;Google Custom Search Engine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Custom Search Engine&lt;/a&gt;, which is what I went for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other dynamic part of an ordinary blog is the comment section. Again, the easiest way to fix this is relying on a 3rd party comments plugin like &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo offers &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/extras/comments&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; for this and makes it fairly simple to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Hugo does not come with search or a comments section as built-in features, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take issue with this as I quickly found ways to integrate them anyways. So to me, these two disadvantages are easily outweighed by the advantages of a static website. Your website will survive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot_effect&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slashdotting&lt;/a&gt; and the only required maintenance is literally making sure your web server stays online (and I think I&amp;rsquo;m in pretty good shape with Github).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress is the most popular content management system (CMS) for a reason. There are countless commercial websites and personal blogs powered by Wordpress along with thousands of customizable plugins. You don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to know how to program to build a beautiful-looking Wordpress site. But what you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know is that the typical CMS driven website works by building each page on-demand, fetching content from a database and running it through a template engine. This means each page is assembled from templates and content on each request to the server. However, this is usually completely unnecessary overhead and only adds complexity, performance problems and security issues. After all, most websites only change when the content authors or their design team makes changes. As the sole proprieter of andrewrgoss.com, this was the case for me and my pages were often quite slow in loading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are someone who is comfortable coding and looking to publish a personal website/blog that is lightning-quick, highly customizable and free (open-source), Hugo may be a good choice for you. For me it has also been a great way to practice front-end development as most of my time is spent on the back-end. And if you ever get stuck, there is a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo community&lt;/a&gt; for Q&amp;amp;A support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;TL;DR&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; Data engineer, technical consultant, and business intelligence developer working to solve analytic challenges at the intersection of marketing and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My career has been tied closely to the convergence of marketing and technology (martech) and the ever-increasing reliance on data at the heart of it all. With petabytes of data being collected at every turn through digital and offline interactions, I work to wrangle this data and derive value from it. My projects span the gamut: writing algorithms, managing/collating data, interpreting/visualizing the data, and communicating important findings to key stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-background:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;My Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently a manager for Media Systems and Technology at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;, where we use a variety of evolving technologies to build the systems and architectures behind business intelligence tools used extensively by global marketing teams. Through the use of data science, our teams summarize the data story for each client in order to measure campaign effectiveness, apply predictive modeling, and ultimately influence consumer brand affiliations and buying patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 5+ years I have gained experience as both a developer and a marketer in leveraging people, process, and technology. I&amp;rsquo;ve held both client-facing and technical roles while addressing a wide range of business initiatives across industries such as finance, higher education, retail, technology, and telecommunications. During this time I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with numerous high-profile companies including Bank of America, EDMC, Fitbit, Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Sprint, and Reed Elsevier. In supporting these organizations, my cross-functional roles have included data engineering, ETL scripting, database design, application development, operational reporting, database marketing, and marketing automation. I&amp;rsquo;ve helped clients translate large amounts of fragmented data into smarter optimization of marketing/advertising dollars through technical expertise combined with human marketing savviness and business acumen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consultant, I strive to consistently provide quality ongoing services, on-time deliverables, and open communication around project status, risks, and challenges. I am results-oriented, well-organized, self-motivated, and I work to build strong relationships with my clients and team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rate at which technology changes, you can never stop learning new things. I take a proactive approach towards career growth and skill development through a dedicated effort towards continuing education that I write about in this blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across many great &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/resources&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; and ideas that I also &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andrewrgoss&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; about regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help on a data project or have ideas you want to discuss further? &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:andrewrgoss@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Shoot me a note!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of great resources all over the internet. I&amp;rsquo;ve bookmarked hundreds of URLs and this page is my categorized collection of the (free) ones I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be the most helpful. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this and have something to add or find a dead link please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:andrewrgoss@gmail.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shoot me a note&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be building this up more over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#business_intelligence&#34;&gt;Business Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#data_science&#34;&gt;Data Science&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#data_viz&#34;&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#martech&#34;&gt;MarTech&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#programming&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#web_services&#34;&gt;Web Services&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#website_tools&#34;&gt;Website Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-business-intelligence-a-business-intelligence:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;business_intelligence&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Business Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-s-my-activity-page:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s My Activity Page&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This portal reveals everything Google knows about you - every search you&amp;rsquo;ve made, the apps you&amp;rsquo;ve used, the videos you&amp;rsquo;ve watched, and everything in between. Visit to see how your data is being collected, modify activity settings, and delete data that you prefer not retained.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://myactivity.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;myactivity.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;olap-cubes:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;OLAP Cubes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice intro guide on what these are and why they are used.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://olap.com/learn-bi-olap/olap-bi-definitions/olap-cube&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;olap.com/learn-bi-olap/olap-bi-definitions/olap-cube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;transactional-vs-analytical-processing:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Transactional vs. Analytical Processing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good cross-comparison between OLTP and OLAP systems.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://datawarehouse4u.info/OLTP-vs-OLAP.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;datawarehouse4u.info/OLTP-vs-OLAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-data-science-a-data-science:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;data_science&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data Science&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;beginner-s-guide-to-big-data-terminology:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Big Data Terminology&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walkthrough on some of the common lingo of data science, such as DaaS and Neural Networking.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataconomy.com/a-beginners-guide-to-big-data-terminology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dataconomy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;crowdflower-data-for-everyone:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Crowdflower: Data for Everyone&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collection of free, downloadable, and categorized datasets that have gone through the Crowdflower platform.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crowdflower.com/data-for-everyone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;crowdflower.com/data-for-everyone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;kaggle:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offers a means of learning data science through both public and private competitions.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kaggle.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;kdnuggets:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;KDnuggets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website looks like its design hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed since the 90s, but it is home to lots of great content on business analytics, big data, data mining, and data science.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kdnuggets.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kdnuggets.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;r-or-python-for-data-science:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;R or Python for Data Science?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a nice blog post on opendatascience.com that digs into the differences/advantages of using either R or Python for performing data science tasks.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opendatascience.com/blog/r-or-python-for-data-science&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;opendatascience.com/blog/r-or-python-for-data-science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ropensci:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;rOpenSci&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source R packages that allow access to data repositories and provide programmatic access to a variety of scientific data and other real-time metrics of scholarly impact.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ropensci.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ropensci.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;techpizza:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;TechPizza&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site aggregates information around upcoming data-related Meetups and also gives users the ability to browse for slides, code, and video from Meetup tech groups around the world.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://techpizza.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;techpizza.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-data-viz-a-data-visualization:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;data_viz&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-data-studio:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Google Data Studio&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free product lets you connect to all your marketing data and turn that data into beautiful, informative reports that are easy to understand, share, and fully customizable.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://datastudio.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;datastudio.google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-martech-a-martech:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;martech&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;MarTech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;real-story-group:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Real Story Group&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This firm specializes in evaluating vendors in the MarTech space to help you find the right provider among a glut of offerings.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.realstorygroup.com/Vendors-Evaluated&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;realstorygroup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-programming-a-programming:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;bento:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Bento&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A curated collection of tutorials and free learning resources for learning to code in new languages.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bento.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bento.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;codeproject-diving-in-oop:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;CodeProject: Diving in OOP&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive article that covers almost every OOP (object-oriented programming) concept in detail with C# examples.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/771455/Diving-in-OOP&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;codeproject.com/Diving-in-OOP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;overapi:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;OverAPI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge selection of cheat sheets for almost any current programming language and other technologies.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://overapi.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;overapi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-web-services-a-web-services:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;web_services&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Web Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;openweathermap:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;OpenWeatherMap&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;API for accessing current weather data for any location including over 200,000 cities.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://openweathermap.org/api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;openweathermap.org/api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;postman:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Postman&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This free Chrome extension allows developers to explore, test, and build APIs using a powerful collaborative testing and development suite.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getpostman.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;getpostman.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;restful-architecture:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;RESTful Architecture&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical documentation for RESTful web services with references and language-specific examples.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://smartsheet-platform.github.io/api-docs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;smartsheet-platform.github.io/api-docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-a-rest-api:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;What is a REST API?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thorough overview on what REST APIs are and how to use them.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/docapis_what-is-a-rest-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;idratherbewriting.com/docapis_what-is-a-rest-api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-website-tools-a-website-tools:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;website_tools&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Website Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;builtwith:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the URL of a website and quickly find a list of the technologies used to support that site including email services, nameserver providers, JavaScript libraries, widgets, server information, and more.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://builtwith.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;builtwith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;google-design-resizer:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Google Design: Resizer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interactive viewer to see and test how digital products respond to material design breakpoints across desktop, mobile, and tablet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://design.google.com/resizer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;design.google.com/resizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-use-github-pages-to-make-websites:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;How To Use GitHub Pages To Make Websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step-by-step tutorial to getting started with building a website hosted on Github Pages.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://readwrite.com/2013/11/27/github-pages-explained&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;readwrite.com/github-pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;mobile-website-speed-testing-tool:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Mobile Website Speed Testing Tool&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great Google product. Find out how well your site works across mobile and desktop devices by simply entering the URL.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://testmysite.thinkwithgoogle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;testmysite.thinkwithgoogle.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-site-generators:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Static Site Generators&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leaderboard of the top open-source static site generators based on Github stars.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;staticgen.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;website-grader:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Website Grader&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free online tool that grades any website against key metrics such as performance, mobile readiness, SEO, and security.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://website.grader.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;website.grader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;who-is-hosting-this:74f7fb04a75e766307d398251c369a21&#34;&gt;Who Is Hosting This&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allows a user to simply enter the domain name of any site and instantly uncover the identity of the company that is hosting the site.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whoishostingthis.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;whoishostingthis.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on my professional background including additional details around my work history, you can visit my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewrgoss&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data engineer/analyst with 5+ years of experience developing innovative solutions related to data integration, data warehousing, and advanced analytics. I have worked as both a developer and a marketer in leveraging people, process, and technology to address marketing data initiatives across industries such as finance, higher education, retail, technology, and telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;clients-served:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Clients Served&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/BoA_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bank of America&#34; title=&#34;Bank of America&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/Correlsense_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Correlsense&#34; title=&#34;Correlsense&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/DBC_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Diversified Communications&#34; title=&#34;Diversified Communications&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/EDMC_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Education Management Corporation&#34; title=&#34;Education Management Corporation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/Fitbit_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fitbit&#34; title=&#34;Fitbit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/HP_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;HP Inc.&#34; title=&#34;HP Inc.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/HPE_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hewlett Packard Enterprise&#34; title=&#34;Hewlett Packard Enterprise&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/Reed_Elsevier_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Reed Elsevier&#34; title=&#34;Reed Elsevier&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/Sprint_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sprint&#34; title=&#34;Sprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/TB_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Taco Bell&#34; title=&#34;Taco Bell&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/UTI_logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Universal Technical Institute&#34; title=&#34;Universal Technical Institute&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-competencies:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Core Competencies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/coding.png&#34; alt=&#34;Application Development&#34; title=&#34;Application Development&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/analysis.png&#34; alt=&#34;Business Intelligence&#34; title=&#34;Business Intelligence&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/database.png&#34; alt=&#34;Database Architecture&#34; title=&#34;Database Architecture&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/gears.png&#34; alt=&#34;Marketing Automation&#34; title=&#34;Marketing Automation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/projectmanagement.png&#34; alt=&#34;Project Management&#34; title=&#34;Project Management&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Application Development, Business Intelligence, Database Architecture, Marketing Automation, Project Management&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other specialties:&lt;/b&gt; data engineering, marketing analytics, application development, consulting, data warehousing, data science, marketing systems, data mining, data transformation, vendor management, data visualization, marketing operations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tools-technologies:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Tools &amp;amp; Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Excel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft Excel&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/msexcel.png&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms159106.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SSRS&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/mssqlserver.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tableau.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tableau&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/tableau.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;BIG DATA:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hadoop&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/hadoop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hive.apache.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hive&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/hive.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gethue.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hue&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/hue.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;CHANGE MANAGEMENT:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/github.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gitlab&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/gitlab.png&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/git.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://subversion.apache.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Subversion&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/subversion.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ETL TOOLS:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms141026.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SSIS&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/mssqlserver.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.talend.com/products/talend-open-studio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Talend Open Studio&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/talend.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;IDES:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visual Studio&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/visual_studio.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/visual_studio_code.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;MARKETING AUTOMATION:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/products/marketing-automation/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eloqua&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/eloqua.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketo.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marketo&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/marketo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPERATING SYSTEMS:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Windows&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/windows.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linux.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Linux&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/linux.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SQL&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/sql.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/z1zx9t92.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;C#&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/csharp.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Python&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/python.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/golang.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDBMS:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/mt590198.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft SQL Server&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/mssqlserver.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/postgresql.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;TEXT EDITORS:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Atom&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/atom.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://notepad-plus-plus.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Notepad++&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/notepad++.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ultraedit.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UltraEdit&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/ultraedit.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;WEB TECHNOLOGIES:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/html5.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascading_Style_Sheets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CSS&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/css3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;XML&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/xml.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JSON&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/json.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RESTful Web Services&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/rest-api.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;WORKFLOW MANAGEMENT:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JIRA&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/jira.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trello&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/trello.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-experience:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Work Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/digitaslbi_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaslbi.com/us&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DigitasLBi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | Oct 2015 - present&lt;br&gt;
Manager, Media Systems &amp;amp; Techology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quickpivot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/quickpivot_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quickpivot.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;QuickPivot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | Apr 2012 - Oct 2015&lt;br&gt;
Technical Consultant | Account Manager | Marketing Specialist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geminiunderwriters.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/gtu_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geminiunderwriters.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gemini Transportation Underwriters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | Jul 2011 - Apr 2012&lt;br&gt;
Marketing Specialist&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search results</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/search/</guid>
      <description>A lot of ad/tracker blockers like Ghostery are blocking Google Custom Search Engine. Allow &lt;i&gt;Google AJAX Search API&lt;/i&gt; to show your search results.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;gcse:searchresults-only linktarget=&#34;_parent&#34;&gt;&lt;/gcse:searchresults-only&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>