<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Engineering Technologies 2021</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/data-engineering-technologies-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/data-engineering-technologies-2021/</guid>
      <description>written by Vijay Ram  Getdbt, It&amp;rsquo;s hitting the sweet spot of Apache Spark by bringing a simplified SQL-based pipeline! Prefect, Designed to make workflow management easier &amp;amp; better compared to Apache Airflow DVC, Open-source version control System for machine learning projects &amp;amp; desired for MLOps  Great_Expectations, Data science testing framework, it&amp;rsquo;s already amazing! Amundsen, An open-sourced data discovery and metadata engine Marquez, Open source metadata with an amazing UI Dagster, A data orchestrator for machine learning, very programming-based &amp;amp; in the similar space of Airflow/Prefect but emphasizes state flow Apache Calcite, Framework for building SQL databases and data management systems without owning data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Engineering Ecosystem in 2021</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/data-engineering-ecosystem-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/data-engineering-ecosystem-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Recently came across this cool cross-sectional LUMAscape visual that depicts the larger ecosystem of data engineering tools and technologies adjacent and complementary to the problems we are solving. Check out the accompanying report by following the link below.

View the full report
*Source: lakeFS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Up with Data Engineering — A Resource Guide</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/keeping-up-with-data-engineering--a-resource-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/keeping-up-with-data-engineering--a-resource-guide/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Kevin Ku on Unsplash
written by Sheel Choksi 
The data engineering space is continuously evolving — there are new open-source projects and tools released all the time, &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; are constantly changing, and data engineers are stretched thinner than ever before as businesses increase their data demands. Not only that, but data engineers have recently seen firsthand the hybridization of the data lake and data warehouse, with modern warehouses blurring the distinction by separating out compute from storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified Web Scraping Using Python Requests &amp; Scraper API</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/simplified-web-scraping-using-python-requests--scraper-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/simplified-web-scraping-using-python-requests--scraper-api/</guid>
      <description>In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve tried out some different web scraping techniques, experimenting with different Python libraries such as BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, and Selenium.
While I was able to extract the data I was looking for from the specific webpages my code was crawling, the internet is a vast place and not all websites are created equal. When doing web scraping at scale, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to scrape sites that are protected by anti-bots like Distil, Akamai, or Cloudflare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Reads to Level Up Your Data Career</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/recommended-reads-to-level-up-your-data-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/recommended-reads-to-level-up-your-data-career/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a list of recommended, categorized articles to peruse, experiment with, and help level up your career in data. Note that many of these are hosted by Medium.com, which sets a limit on the number of free stories you can view. To get around this, tweet out the link and then click it from Twitter or search the title to see if someone else has already tweeted the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Warehouse Pipelines- Basic Concepts &amp; Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/data-warehouse-pipelines--basic-concepts--roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/data-warehouse-pipelines--basic-concepts--roadmap/</guid>
      <description>written by Antony Henao 
 Five processes to improve your data pipeline operability and performance
 Building a data warehouse pipeline can be complex sometimes. If you are starting in this world, you will soon realize there is no right or wrong way to do it. It always depends on your needs.
Yet, there a couple of basic processes you should put in place when building a data pipeline to improve its operability and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Data Lakes Guide — Modern Batch Data Warehousing</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/a-data-lakes-guide--modern-batch-data-warehousing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/a-data-lakes-guide--modern-batch-data-warehousing/</guid>
      <description>written by Daniel Mateus Pires
 Redefining the batch data extraction patterns and the data lake using “Functional Data Engineering”
 The last decades have been greatly transformative for the Data Analytics landscape. With the decrease in storage costs and the adoption of cloud computing, the restrictions that guided the design of data tools were made obsolete and so — the data engineering tools and techniques had to evolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Data Warehouse Anti-Patterns</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/top-4-data-warehouse-anti-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/top-4-data-warehouse-anti-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Ascend blog on Ascend.io
written by Sean Knapp 
 When data warehouses are stretched outside of their core purpose, these once revered systems can put our data and our projects at risk. Below are the four most commonly found data warehouse anti-patterns.
 &amp;ldquo;The best investment is in the tools of one’s own trade.&amp;rdquo; — Benjamin Franklin
The vast array of data, systems, and their interconnectedness continues to grow and is becoming increasingly complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps is NOT Just DevOps for Data</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/dataops-is-not-just-devops-for-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/dataops-is-not-just-devops-for-data/</guid>
      <description>written by DataKitchen 
One common misconception about DataOps is that it is just DevOps applied to data analytics. While a little semantically misleading, the name “DataOps” has one positive attribute. It communicates that data analytics can achieve what software development attained with DevOps. That is to say, DataOps can yield an order of magnitude improvement in quality and cycle time when data teams utilize new tools and methodologies. The specific ways that DataOps achieves these gains reflect the unique people, processes and tools characteristic of data teams (versus software development teams using DevOps).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS &amp; Snowflake vs GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/aws--snowflake-vs-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/aws--snowflake-vs-gcp/</guid>
      <description>written by Stefano Solimito 
When we talk about data, the number of technologies available on the market is overwhelming and staying up to date is a key challenge both for businesses and for engineers.
With this article, Stefano Solimito shares the joys and pains of the learning journey of building a new data platform using some of the most cutting edge technologies available — AWS (Amazon Web Services), Snowflake and Looker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELT Data Pipelining in Snowflake Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/elt-data-pipelining-in-snowflake-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/elt-data-pipelining-in-snowflake-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>written by Christopher Tao 
In my previous post:
Building Snowpipe on Azure Blob Storage Using Azure Portal Web UI for Snowflake Data Warehouse
Snowpipe was introduced to be utilized for automatically discovering new data files in cloud storage (e.g. Azure Blob Storage) and then load the data into a certain table.
Snowpipe is a very convenient tool for the above purposes. However, Snowpipe itself is only considered as the “E” (Extract) of ELT, because only COPY INTO command is allowed in a Snowpipe creating statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of SQL-Based Data Modeling and DataOps</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/the-rise-of-sql-based-data-modeling-and-dataops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/the-rise-of-sql-based-data-modeling-and-dataops/</guid>
      <description>written by Thanh Dinh 
The resurgence of SQL-based RDBMS If there is one analytics trend we can all agree on, it is that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a vast increase in the amount of business data collected in the past decade. A typical business today uses dozens if not hundreds of cloud-based, subscription-as-a-service software, for all sorts of purposes. Together with more traditional in-house enterprise software, the average business produces a mountain of data today, compared to just a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps Is Here To Stay</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/dataops-is-here-to-stay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/dataops-is-here-to-stay/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Stephen Dawson on Unsplash
written by Pedro Martinez 
What Is DataOps? DataOps is a discipline that has become a necessity in a market where the demand for access to data assets and data products is skyrocketing. The inability of data platform teams and data management platforms to keep pace with the demands placed on them by DevOps-enabled teams led to the development of DataOps.[i]
In a nutshell, DataOps brings together data scientists, analysts, developers, and operations to work on the entire product/service lifecycle, from the design stage to production support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build GraphQL Server with Ruby</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/build-graphql-server-with-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/build-graphql-server-with-ruby/</guid>
      <description>TUTORIAL LINK

*Source: How To GraphQL
Built my own GraphQL server using the following technologies:
 Ruby on Rails: the most popular library for building applications in Ruby GraphQL Gem: the most popular library for building GraphQL applications GraphiQL: An in-browser IDE for exploring GraphQL, which comes bundled with GraphQL Gem  Resources  Official Specification Graphcool (Self-Hosted GraphQL BaaS)  GraphQL Queries Run # Welcome to GraphiQL # # Keyboard shortcuts: # # Prettify Query: Shift-Ctrl-P (or press the prettify button above) # Run Query: Ctrl-Enter (or press the play button above) # Auto Complete: Ctrl-Space (or just start typing) # query getAllLinks { allLinks { id url description postedBy { name votes { link { description } } } } } query allLinksFilter { allLinks(filter: {descriptionContains: &amp;quot;testing&amp;quot; OR: {descriptionContains: &amp;quot;best&amp;quot;} }) { description } } query LinksPagination { allLinks(first: 1, skip: 1) { id } } # https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/graphql-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/graphql-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>TUTORIAL LINK

*Source: How To GraphQL
Introduction Most applications today have the need to fetch data from a server where that data is stored in a database. It’s the responsibility of the API to provide an interface to the stored data that fits an application’s needs.
 APIs have become ubiquitous components of software infrastructures. In short, an API defines how a client can load data from a server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Learn to Code with Ruby</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/udemy--learn-to-code-with-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/udemy--learn-to-code-with-ruby/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE
COURSE LINK

What is Ruby?  An object-oriented programming language A popular language across the world Released in 1995 by Yukihiro Matsumoto (&amp;ldquo;Matz&amp;rdquo;) Open-source project in development today Available for both Windows and Mac OS operating systems  Ruby Design Principles  Ruby is a high-level programming language. Ruby is an interpreted language. It does not need to be compiled. Ruby code is read top-to-bottom, line by line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills for Being a Good Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/skills-for-being-a-good-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/skills-for-being-a-good-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Benjamin Rogojan 
A data engineer specializes in several specific technical aspects. Data engineers have solid automation/programming skills, ETL design, understand systems, data modeling, SQL, and usually some other more niche skills. For instance, some data engineers start to dabble with R and data analytics. This will also be driven by their specific role. As a data engineer, I have been asked to set up basic websites, develop APIs and create models and algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Architect the Perfect Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/how-to-architect-the-perfect-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/how-to-architect-the-perfect-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>Key warehousing techniques made simple
 written by Lewis Gavin 
On the surface, it may seem like a lot has changed in recent years in regards to data collection, storage and warehousing. The introduction and takeover of NoSQL, “Big Data”, Graphing and Streaming technologies may appear to have changed the landscape, but there are some fundamentals that remain.
In my current role, we use Amazon Redshift for our data warehousing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Data Warehousing</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/future-of-data-warehousing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/future-of-data-warehousing/</guid>
      <description>written by Simon Späti (with some grammatical edits by me) 
Today, there are 6,500 people on LinkedIn who call themselves data engineers according to stitchdata.com. In San Francisco alone, there are 6,600 job listings for this same title. The number of data engineers has doubled in the past year, but engineering leaders still find themselves faced with a significant shortage of data engineering talent. So is it really the future of data warehousing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Pillars of Analytics</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/4-pillars-of-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/4-pillars-of-analytics/</guid>
      <description>written by Julien Kervizic 
 There are four key pillars that rule the lifecycle of analytics projects, from data acquisition, processing to surfacing and actioning on the data. Each of these contribute to a significant part of the value chain of analytics.
 Pillar 1: Acquisition The data acquisition pillar consists of a wide range of tasks, system and technology knowledge, one needs to possessed in order to be effective in acquiring the required data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/functional-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/functional-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>written by Maxime Beauchemin 
Batch data processing — historically known as ETL — is extremely challenging. It&amp;rsquo;s time-consuming, brittle, and often unrewarding. Not only that, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to operate, evolve, and troubleshoot.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how applying the functional programming paradigm to data engineering can bring a lot of clarity to the process. This post distills fragments of wisdom accumulated while working at Yahoo, Facebook, Airbnb and Lyft, with the perspective of well over a decade of data warehousing and data engineering experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Data Engineer&#39;s Guide To Non-Traditional Data Storages</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/a-data-engineers-guide-to-non-traditional-data-storages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/a-data-engineers-guide-to-non-traditional-data-storages/</guid>
      <description>For data engineers, the most important aspects of data storages are how they index, shard, and aggregate data.
 This post originally appeared on Toptal and was written by Ken Hu.
Data Engineering With the rise of big data and data science, many engineering roles are being challenged and expanded. One new-age role is data engineering.
Originally, the purpose of data engineering was the loading of external data sources and the designing of databases (designing and developing pipelines to collect, manipulate, store, and analyze data).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner’s Guide to Data Engineering - A 3-Part Series</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/beginners-guide-to-data-engineering---a-3-part-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/beginners-guide-to-data-engineering---a-3-part-series/</guid>
      <description>written by Robert Chang
Overview This is an excellent 3-part series of articles written from the vantage point of a data scientist looking to learn more about the field of data engineering.
Organization of This Guide The scope of the discussion is not be exhaustive and is designed heavily around Airflow, batch data processing, and SQL-like languages. That said, this focus should not prevent readers from getting a basic understanding of data engineering and may pique interest to learn more about this fast-growing, emerging field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- Building Resilient Streaming Systems on GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_streaming_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_streaming_systems/</guid>
      <description> 
COURSE LINK
GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Building Resilient Streaming Systems 
Modules &amp;amp; Lab Exercises Resources </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- GCP Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_big_data_ml_fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_big_data_ml_fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
COURSE CERTIFICATE
GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals 
Module Lab Exercises Module 2: Foundations of GCP Compute and Storage  Create a Compute Engine Instance Interact with Cloud Storage  Module 3: Data Analysis on the Cloud  Setup Rentals Data in Cloud SQL Recommendations ML with Dataproc  Module 4: Scaling Data Analysis: Compute with GCP  Create ML dataset with BigQuery Carry out ML with TensorFLow Invoke Machine Learning APIs  View my code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- Leveraging Unstructured Data on GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/coursera--leveraging-unstructured-data-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/coursera--leveraging-unstructured-data-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
COURSE CERTIFICATE

Modules &amp;amp; Lab Exercises Note: These exercises were spun up in temporary cloud instances and thus are no longer available for viewing.
Module 1: Introduction to Cloud Dataproc What Qualifies as Unstructured Data? Dataproc Eases Hadoop Management Cloud Dataproc Architecture Lab 1: Create a Dataproc Cluster  Prepare a bucket and a cluster initialization script Create a Dataproc Hadoop Cluster customized to use Google Cloud API Enable secure access to Dataproc cluster Explore Hadoop operations   Use Cloud storage instead of HDFS so you can shut down a Hadoop cluster when it is not actually running a job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc on GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_unstructured_dataproc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_unstructured_dataproc/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
COURSE CERTIFICATE
GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc 
Modules &amp;amp; Lab Exercises Note: These exercises were spun up in temporary cloud instances and thus are no longer available for viewing.
Module 1: Introduction to Cloud Dataproc What Qualifies as Unstructured Data? Dataproc Eases Hadoop Management Cloud Dataproc Architecture Lab 1: Create a Dataproc Cluster  Prepare a bucket and a cluster initialization script Create a Dataproc Hadoop Cluster customized to use Google Cloud API Enable secure access to Dataproc cluster Explore Hadoop operations   Use Cloud storage instead of HDFS so you can shut down a Hadoop cluster when it is not actually running a job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_serverless_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_serverless_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description> 
COURSE LINK
GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow 
Modules &amp;amp; Lab Exercises Resources </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow on GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_serverless_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/gcp_serverless_ml/</guid>
      <description> 
COURSE LINK
GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow 
Modules &amp;amp; Lab Exercises Resources </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera- GCP Big Data and ML Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/coursera--gcp-big-data-and-ml-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/coursera--gcp-big-data-and-ml-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
COURSE CERTIFICATE

Module Lab Exercises Module 2: Foundations of GCP Compute and Storage  Create a Compute Engine Instance Interact with Cloud Storage  Module 3: Data Analysis on the Cloud  Setup Rentals Data in Cloud SQL Recommendations ML with Dataproc  Module 4: Scaling Data Analysis: Compute with GCP  Create ML dataset with BigQuery Carry out ML with TensorFLow Invoke Machine Learning APIs  View my code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/getting-started-with-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/getting-started-with-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>written by Richard Taylor

This is an excellent overview article that covers essential knowledge areas related to data engineering. Specifically the author digs into the following topics:
 A brief history of the big data sector and why it exists.
 What is big data? Terminology guide  What a data engineer is and how and why the role came to be.
 What is a data engineer? Fundamentals and ongoing trends Roles and responsibilities as a data engineer  Big picture overview of the technologies data engineers have been using thus far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Engineers vs. Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>The two positions are not interchangeable—and misperceptions of their roles can hurt teams and compromise productivity.
 written by Jesse Anderson
View original article

It’s important to understand the differences between a data engineer and a data scientist. Misunderstanding or not knowing these differences are making teams fail or underperform with big data.
A key misunderstanding is the strengths and weaknesses of each position. I think some of these misconceptions come from the diagrams that are used to describe data scientists and data engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE
COURSE MATERIALS

Description  Learn the concepts of Spark&amp;rsquo;s Resilient Distributed Datastores Get a crash course in the Scala programming language Develop and run Spark jobs quickly using Scala Translate complex analysis problems into iterative or multi-stage Spark scripts Scale up to larger data sets using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Elastic MapReduce service Understand how Hadoop YARN distributes Spark across computing clusters Practice using other Spark technologies, like Spark SQL, DataFrames, DataSets, Spark Streaming, and GraphX  What I got from this course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Streaming with Spark and Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/twitter_streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/twitter_streaming/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Twitter Streaming

Go to: DataChatter | TweetLength
PopularHashtags.scala This is a Spark streaming script that monitors live tweets from Twitter and keeps track of the 10 most popular hashtags as tweets are received.
Each hashtag is mapped to a key/value pair of (hashtag, 1) so they can be counted up over a 5-minute sliding window with this line of code:
val hashtagCounts = hashtagKeyValues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Similar Movies from One Million Ratings on EMR</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/mov_sim_ml_1m_emr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/mov_sim_ml_1m_emr/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Creating Similar Movies from One Million Ratings on EMR

I completed an exercise of compiling a .jar file from my Scala code through IntelliJ IDEA, uploading this to a S3 bucket I created, and then running a Spark job on a AWS EMR cluster that I spun up. Here are the steps I took with screenshots, since I terminated my EMR cluster at the end to avoid incurring unnecessary costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps- Next Gen Data Engineering Organization</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</guid>
      <description>Large enterprises are experiencing a foundational shift in how they view their data and structure their data engineering teams. As organizations capture more data than ever before, and store it in an ever-increasing variety of data stores, the prospect of competing on analytics becomes more tantalizing than ever.
  written by Andy Palmer
View original article

The challenges of using data at scale, however, is rooted in the &amp;ldquo;data debt&amp;rdquo; accumulated over time by enterprises struggling to manage the extreme volume and variety of their data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why 2018 Will Be The Year Of The Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-the-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-the-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Alex Woodie, Managing Editor of Datanami
The shortage of data scientists - those triple-threat types who possess advanced statistics, business, and coding skills - has been well-documented over the years. But increasingly, businesses are facing a shortage of another key individual on the big data team who&amp;rsquo;s critical to achieving success - the data engineer.
 Data engineers are tasked with building and maintaining the pipes that serve up fresh and accurate data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Learn</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>As 2018 began, I spent some time thinking about my goals for this year. An area that I wanted to focus on is improving upon how I learn. Many have argued that the ability to learn is the most valuable skill you can possess throughout your career and working in the ever-changing field of technology, I certainly would not disagree.
So I decided to invest in the 10 Steps to Learn Anything Quickly course offered by Simple Programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping with Python</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/web_scraping_py/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/web_scraping_py/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Web Scraping with Python

Following a Boston Python Project Night event that I attended (where my group focused on web scraping techniques), I wanted to try out some web scraping on my own with Python.
 Web scraping is a technique used to extract data from websites through an automated process.
 Dataset A good site for web scraping that was recommended to me at the event is College Sailing’s Techscore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete Java Masterclass</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--complete-java-masterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--complete-java-masterclass/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK

I have completed numerous sections of this course to improve my core knowledge of Java. One of the reasons I frequently choose Udemy for my learning needs is that it offers a one-time cost (as opposed to monthly recurring charges) for lifetime access to the course content.
Other Learning Resources Oracle Java™ Tutorials &amp;ndash; Trail: Learning the Java Language
Cheat Sheets Java Classes
Java Keywords
Java Operator Precedence Table</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Engineer Notes</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/effective-engineer-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/effective-engineer-notes/</guid>
      <description>Some great reference notes from a highly recommended &amp;#x1F44D; book for engineers looking to reach the next level in their careers.
 By Edmond Lau
theeffectiveengineer.com
What&amp;rsquo;s an Effective Engineer?  They are the people who get things done. Effective Engineers produce results.  Adopt the Right Mindsets Focus on High Leverage Activities  Leverage = Impact Produced / Time Invested Use Leverage as Your Yardstick for Effectiveness 80% of the impact comes from 20% of the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Successful Side Project</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/how-to-start-a-successful-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/how-to-start-a-successful-side-project/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on Simple Programmer.
written by Alexander Petkov
View original article

Do you ever feel like you are confident in only one particular field? Like you know only one tiny corner of the vast software universe? Then, the minute you try to escape it and work on something different, you get frustrated. And if you need to build a complete, functional project—from scratch—with:
Initial research and machine setup (packages, installments)Managing dependencies (libraries, build tools, automations)The whole business logic plus high test coverageProduction deployment … then somebody else has to do everything except the little corner of your comfort zone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/becoming-a-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/becoming-a-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Sergio Sola (with some grammatical edits by me)
Becoming a Data Engineer I am a software engineer working at HelloFresh. I have been with the company for five years so far. Before HelloFresh and in this company I had different roles.
I started my career as a web developer doing everything, something that nowadays is called &amp;lsquo;full stack developer&amp;rsquo; (I have a firm opinion about that position, and it is not good, but that would be another article).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 Potential Pitfalls In Mastering Programming</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/25-potential-pitfalls-in-mastering-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/25-potential-pitfalls-in-mastering-programming/</guid>
      <description>written by Antonio Cangiano
 I wanted to share this post as it really resonated with me. I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered many of these at times during my coding journey and plan to reread this.
 I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you what I see as &amp;ldquo;25&amp;rdquo; common pitfalls when learning to program (or working towards mastering programming). Many of these points affect both beginners and professionals alike — myself very much included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Path to Learning Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/my-path-to-learning-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/my-path-to-learning-scala/</guid>
      <description>I recently joined a new data engineering team at DigitasLBi and Scala is the predominant language being used. Having never coded in this language, I sought to quickly learn it and wanted to share the numerous resources I came across and bookmarked.
The first place I usually turn when learning something new is to complete an introductory online course with videos and exercises. The most popular course for Scala is Functional Programming Principles in Scala on Coursera and it is taught by the inventor of the language (Martin Odersky), so I gave it a whirl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget App</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/budget_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/budget_app/</guid>
      <description>
Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; My projects
Planning Guide
View project 
This project put all kinds of different JavaScript concepts from the Complete JavaScript Course I completed into practice.
View my project
View my code on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DOM Pig Game</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/dom_pig_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/dom_pig_game/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; My projects

Part of the Complete JavaScript Course I completed, this project put JavaScript concepts from the section on DOM manipulation and events into practice.
GAME RULES:  The game has 2 players, playing in rounds In each turn, a player rolls a dice as many times as he/she wishes. Each result get added to his ROUND score BUT, if the player rolls a 1, all his/her ROUND score gets lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/advanced_js_objects_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/advanced_js_objects_functions/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Advanced JavaScript: Objections and Functions 
Summary  Every JavaScript object has a prototype property, which makes inheritance possible in JavaScript; The prototype property of an object is where we put methods and properties that we want other objects to inherit; The Constructor&amp;rsquo;s prototype property is NOT the prototype of the Constructor itself; it&amp;rsquo;s the prototype of ALL instances that are created through it; When a certain method (or property) is called, the search starts in the object itself, and if it cannot be found, the search moves on to the object&amp;rsquo;s prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/how_js_works_behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/how_js_works_behind/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; How JavaScript Works Behind the Scenes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/js_browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/js_browser/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; JavaScript in the Browser: DOM Manipulation and Events</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/js_language_basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/js_language_basics/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course &amp;gt;&amp;gt; JavaScript language basics 
Introduction to JavaScript What is JavaScript?  JavaScript is a lightweight, cross-platform, object-oriented computer programming language. JavaScript is one of the three core technologies of web development. JavaScript is most commonly used as part of webpages. Today, JavaScript can be used in different places:  Client-side: JavaScript was traditionally only used in the browser Server-side: Thanks to node.js, we can use JavaScript on the server as well  JavaScript is what made modern web development possible:  Dynamic effects and interactivity; Modern web applications that we can interact with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Complete JavaScript Course</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/udemy--complete-javascript-course/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE
Design and Coding Resources

This course represented my official foray into learning JavaScript. Up to this point I&amp;rsquo;d only used it on occasion with no formal training, as my focus has been predominantly on back-end data engineering. I wanted to gain a closer perspective on full-stack development, and JavaScript is a core front-end technology for me to have as part of my stack. This course covers the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Go Language Really Good For?</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/whats-the-go-language-really-good-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/whats-the-go-language-really-good-for/</guid>
      <description>written by Serdar Yegulalp
 InfoWorld examines the strengths, weaknesses, use cases, and future directions of Google&amp;rsquo;s hit programming language
 During its eight-plus years in the wild, Google’s Go language—with version 1.8.1 out as of April 2017—has evolved from being a curiosity for alpha geeks to being the battle-tested programming language behind some of the world’s most important cloud-centric projects.
Why was Go chosen by the developers of such projects as Docker and Kubernetes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Productive Data Engineering Team?</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/what-is-a-productive-data-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/what-is-a-productive-data-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>written by Jesse Anderson
 Merging the gaps between data science and engineering, and what each side can learn from the other.
 In my experience working with data engineering teams, I find that most teams don’t realize they have to change their thinking about data and systems to be successful with big data. Data engineering teams need to think about how data is valuable and at what scale the data is coming in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 Big Data Landscape</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-2017-big-data-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-2017-big-data-landscape/</guid>
      <description>Just released - an excellent &amp;ldquo;State of the Union&amp;rdquo; roundup of the key trends in the 2017 data ecosystem. Some high level trends and questions that are explored in this comprehensive article:
 Big data + AI = the new stack. Big data provides the pipes, and AI provides the smarts. Enterprise budgets - follow the money Enterprise data moving to the cloud As the big data landscape gets busier every passing year, is big data consolidation coming?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With NSQ for Go</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/getting-started-with-nsq-for-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/getting-started-with-nsq-for-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently working on software application project at Digitas where we adopted NSQ as part of our microservices architecture. With this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to share how you can get started with NSQ by sending and receiving a simple message by writing some Go code.
What is NSQ? Per the official website, NSQ is a realtime distributed messaging platform designed to operate at scale, handling billions of messages per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-rise-of-the-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-rise-of-the-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Maxime Beauchemin
I joined Facebook in 2011 as a business intelligence engineer. By the time I left in 2013, I was a data engineer.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t promoted or assigned to this new role. Instead, Facebook came to realize that the work we were doing transcended classic business intelligence. The role we&amp;rsquo;d created for ourselves was a new discipline entirely.
My team was at forefront of this transformation. We were developing new skills, new ways of doing things, new tools, and&amp;ndash;more often than not&amp;ndash;turning our backs to traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDFS DCM Matchtables V2</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/hdfs_dcm_v2_logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/hdfs_dcm_v2_logs/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; HDFS DCM Matchtables V2 
Overview This is my code that pulls down daily DoubleClick Campaign Manager (DCM) log files (v2) from Google Cloud Storage (GCS) and loads them into Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) for use in Hive queries. The script fully replaces matchtable_v2 files with each day&amp;rsquo;s new log file on HDFS. Match tables are demoed here, but it is imperative to frequently download other log files that change more often (ex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs
 Unit_1 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; What_is_Hadoop_Part1
Unit_1 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; What_is_Hadoop_Part2
 Unit_2 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Hadoop_Architecture_Part1
Unit_2 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Hadoop_Architecture_Part2
Unit_2 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; HDFS_Command_Line
Unit_2 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Hadoop_Architecture_Lab
 Unit_3 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Hadoop_Administration
 Unit_4 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; MapReduce
Unit_4 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Pig_Hive
Unit_4 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Flume_Sqoop_Oozie</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_1_what_is_hadoop_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_1_what_is_hadoop_part1/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_1_What_is_Hadoop_Part1 
 Hello everyone and welcome to Hadoop Fundamentals What is Hadoop. My name is Asma Desai and I will be covering this topic.
In this video we will explain what is Hadoop and what is Big Data. We will define some Hadoop-related open source projects and give some examples of Hadoop in action. Finally we will end off with some Big Data solutions and the Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_1_what_is_hadoop_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_1_what_is_hadoop_part2/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_1_What_is_Hadoop_Part2 
 This is a list of some other open source project related to Hadoop:
 Eclipse is a popular IDE donated by IBM to the open-source community Lucene is a text search engine library written in Java Hbase is a Hadoop database Hive provides data warehousing tools to extract, transform and load (ETL) data, and query this data stored in Hadoop files Pig is a high level language that generates MapReduce code to analyze large data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hdfs_command_line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hdfs_command_line/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_2_HDFS_Command_Line 
 Welcome to HDFS command line interface. In this presentation, I will cover the general usage of the HDFS command line interface and commands specific to HDFS. Other commands should be familiar to anyone with UNIX experience and will not be covered.
The HDFS can be manipulated through a Java API or through a command line interface. All commands for manipulating HDFS through Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s command line interface begin with hdfs, a space, and dfs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_lab/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_2_Hadoop_Architecture_Lab 
 Lab exercises</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_part1/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_2_Hadoop_Architecture_Part1 
 Welcome to the unit of Hadoop Fundamentals on Hadoop architecture. I will begin with a terminology review and then cover the major components of Hadoop. We will see what types of nodes can exist in a Hadoop cluster and talk about how Hadoop uses replication to lessen data loss. Finally I will explain an important feature of Hadoop called &amp;ldquo;rack awareness&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;network topology awareness&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_2_hadoop_architecture_part2/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_2_Hadoop_Architecture_Part2 
 Hadoop 2.2 brought about architectural changes to MapReduce. As Hadoop has matured, people have found that it can be used for more than running MapReduce jobs. But to keep each new framework from having its own resource manager and scheduler, that would compete with the other framework resource managers and schedulers, it was decided to have the recourse manager and schedulers to be external to any framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_3_hadoop_administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_3_hadoop_administration/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_3_Hadoop_Administration 
 Welcome to the unit on Hadoop Administration. The agenda covers adding nodes to a cluster, verifying the health of a cluster, and stopping / starting components. Then the unit covers configuring Hadoop and setting up rack topology. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with adding and removing nodes from a cluster.
Adding nodes can be performed from the Ambari Console. To do so requires either the ip address or hostname of the node to be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_flume_sqoop_oozie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_flume_sqoop_oozie/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_4_Flume_Sqoop_Oozie 
 Now let us look at moving data into Hadoop. We will begin by looking at Flume&amp;rsquo;s architecture, then examining the three modes it can run in followed by a look at the event data model. Flume is an open source software program developed by Cloudera that acts as a service for aggregating and moving large amounts of data around a Hadoop cluster as the data is produced or shortly thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_mapreduce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_mapreduce/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_4_MapReduce 
 Welcome to Hadoop Fundamentals, Hadoop Components. In this unit I will discuss the MapReduce Philosophy, describe the usage of Pig and Hive, talk about how to get data into Hadoop through the use of Flume and Sqoop and finally describe how to schedule and control job execution using Oozie.
First I need to set the boundaries for this unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_pig_hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/lesson_transcripts_labs/unit_4_pig_hive/</guid>
      <description>Big Data University- Hadoop 101 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Lesson Transcripts/Labs &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Unit_4_Pig_Hive 
 Pig and Hive have much in common. They all translate high-level languages into MapReduce jobs so that the programmer can work at a higher level than he or she would when writing MapReduce jobs in Java or other lower-level languages supported by Hadoop using Hadoop streaming. The high level languages offered by Pig and Hive let you write programs that are much smaller than the equivalent Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</guid>
      <description>Course Code: BD0111EN
Course Certificate
Course Link
IBM Analytics Demo Cloud
Lesson Transcripts/Labs  My goal in taking this course was to expand upon my knowledge around Apache Hadoop, a free, open source, Java-based programming framework. Topics in this course include:
 Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s architecture and core components, such as MapReduce and the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS). Adding/removing nodes from Hadoop clusters, how to check available disk space on each node, and how to modify configuration parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need Both Data Scientists &amp; Data Engineers</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</guid>
      <description>written by Neeraj Chadha
When it comes to the medical profession, doctors get all the glory. In the world of IoT, it&amp;rsquo;s data scientists who get most of the attention and acclaim. They extract critical intelligence from big data so businesses can make informed decisions on the spot. But they don&amp;rsquo;t do their work in a vacuum. Data scientists can&amp;rsquo;t dazzle their industries without data engineers. These unheralded champions, equivalent to nurses, ensure that big data keeps flowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Science Industry: Who Does What</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</guid>
      <description>Great infographic from DataCamp that lays out the roles and skills associated with a data science team. As a data engineer within this group, these are the kind of people I work with day-to-day.

*Source: DataCamp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Python for Data Structures &amp; Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--python-for-data-structures--algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--python-for-data-structures--algorithms/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
Jupyter Notebooks
 I took this course to get some experience using Jupyter Notebooks and furthered my Python skills in a couple of areas:
 Algorithm Analysis and Big-O Notation Array Sequences  Additionally, this course offers video content on the &amp;lsquo;soft skills&amp;rsquo; needed to advance a career in technology such as personal branding, building a strong professional network, and practicing technical questions that could be asked on a future interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stages of the Analytics Life Cycle</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Across industries, the applied use of data to inform business decisions has become a foundational (arguably critical) element of business. The end goal is to ultimately derive actionable insights from vast amounts of data being collected but it takes a series of activities/tasks to arrive at this juncture. Here is a description of each stage of the analytics life cycle:
 Data Acquisition – This may involve scraping data, interfacing with APIs, querying relational and non-relational databases, or defining strategy in relation to what data to pursue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Data Engineers &amp; Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/comparing-data-engineers--data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/comparing-data-engineers--data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Data engineer and data scientist are the two most popular career tracks in big data - but how do they compare? At a high level, data engineers are concerned with data infrastructure, while data scientists are concerned with analysis.
Like data scientists, data engineers write code. They’re highly analytical, and are interested in data visualization. Unlike data scientists — and inspired by a more mature parent, software engineering — data engineers build tools, infrastructure, frameworks, and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report- The State of Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an excellent report by Stitch on the state of data engineering.
Today, there are 6,500 people on LinkedIn who call themselves data engineers. In San Francisco alone, there are 6,600 job listings for this same title. The number of data engineers has doubled in the past year, but engineering leaders still find themselves faced with a significant shortage of data engineering talent.
The need for data talent is born from a fundamental shift: tech companies are now data companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google DCM/DFA Reporting/Trafficking API for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/dcm-dfa-reporting-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/dcm-dfa-reporting-api/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Google DCM/DFA Reporting/Trafficking API for PostgreSQL 
This is a Python script I developed for programmatically generating Google DCM/DFA report data and inserting into PostgreSQL. There is additionally the option of running a report that contains floodlight tags - my code flattens this for the PostgreSQL staging table structure.
DCM/DFA Reporting and Trafficking API v2.8 is used in this code. A detailed reference of the API can be accessed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Reporting API for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/ga_reporting_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/ga_reporting_api/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Google Analytics Reporting API for PostgreSQL 
This is a Python script I developed for programmatically accessing report data in Google Analytics and inserting into PostgreSQL.
Google Analytics Reporting API V4 is used in this code. A detailed reference of the API can be accessed here.
In this example, a GA summary report is generated (using the JSON below) and inserted into a PostgreSQL staging table with the same name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys With PuTTY and Cygwin for Windows</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>In my work at Digitas, I need to login to a number of client-specific Linux machines via a terminal emulator (there is no UI for these remote environments) from my local Windows laptop. For this my team uses Cygwin, a Linux-like environment for Windows making it possible to port software running on POSIX systems (such as Linux, BSD, and Unix systems) to Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to login of course just using a standard username/password combination with Mosh or SSH at the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Ultimate Python Programming Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/udemy--ultimate-python-programming-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE  I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Python more for work and took this course to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of the language. Previously, I had been wanting to add Python to my personal tech stack for some time as it is a powerful (and popular) all-purpose programming language. It is a high-level language, meaning it looks more like a readable, human language than a low-level language does. The user-friendly syntax makes it one of the easier languages to learn and it is also one of the most commonly-used languages for analytics, data mining, and data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH With Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever written code of any kind for professional and personal purposes, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely come across the concept of Source Control Management (SCM). When I first became a developer, I used Subversion as my SCM tool but have since switched to the more popular Git. I use git to commit the latest versions of code in both Linux and Windows environments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on Windows in this post as this is the operating system for my personal computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Science Conference East</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</guid>
      <description>In May 2016 I attended my first Open Data Science Conference in Boston. There were some 3,000+ data science practioners that came together at the Boston Convention &amp;amp; Exhibition Center to share ideas about this rapidly changing discipline. The following topics were covered throughout the conference:
 Deep Learning Machine Learning Predictive Analytics Python Stan R Julia Hadoop Spark Scikit-learn Natural Language Processing  I attended sessions on popular data science statistical models and using Python for data science, where we worked through this example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Disciplines Compared to Data Science</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Came across an excellent article on Data Science Central that digs into the differences between data science, data mining, machine learning, statistics, operations research, and so on. The author compares several analytic disciplines that overlap to explain the differences and common denominators. Typical job titles, types of analyses, and industries traditionally attached to each discipline are also detailed.
Read more
*Source: Data Science Central</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWSome Day Boston</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/awsome-day-boston/</guid>
      <description>In March 2016 I joined Amazon Web Services for an all-day training event at the Westin Copley Place in Boston. The workshop provided a step-by-step introduction to the core AWS services for compute, storage, database and networking. AWS technical experts explained key features and use cases, shared best practices, and walked through technical demos. We specifically covered the following topics:
 Module 1: AWS Introduction and History Module 2: Infrastructure Services: Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon EBS, and Amazon VPC Module 3: Security, Identity, and Access Management: IAM Module 4: Databases: Amazon DynamoDB and Amazon RDS Module 5: AWS Elasticity and Management Tools: Auto Scaling, Elastic Load Balancing, Amazon CloudWatch, and AWS Trusted Advisor  The day was a great for networking, learning more about cloud computing (from the clear market leader in this space) and how to get started on AWS Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caleb Doxsey- An Introduction to Programming in Go</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/caleb-doxsey--an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</guid>
      <description>BOOK LINK  Go (Golang) is an open source programming language that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software. I first started using Go through my work at DigitasLBi. My department adopted this language as one of our tech stacks for the following reasons:
 It’s open source (i.e. free) and intended to be simple yet expressive. It’s intended to be a good middleware layer to provide for both quick one-off applications as well as large collaborative code bases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gologger</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/gologger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/gologger/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Gologger
 Gologger incorporates the elements of the best user-designed logging tools for Go. It primarily makes use of CoLog, a prefix-based execution logging tool.
The goal of this tool is to provide a simple, easy-to-use, customizable framework for implementing leveled, environment-based logging for new Go applications.
Usage This tool is setup to customize logging outputs based on the environment command line flag. It uses CoLog to read and parse the standard log output, effectively acting as an extension of the default log library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Programming for Beginners in C#</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2015/udemy--programming-for-beginners-in-c/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE  I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on Windows servers throughout my career, which initially got me started with this language. Learning some of the Base Class Library (BCL) of the Microsoft .NET Framework and using these classes through C# has helped me automate various tasks within these environments.
My goal in taking this course was to strengthen my knowledge around the fundamentals of C# programming (and objected-oriented programming in general) and to get more practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched from Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2015/why-i-switched-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve believed in the importance of having a blog but have struggled to keep one going. I started out using Blogger back in the day and most recently was using Wordpress. But there were features about these blogging platforms that consistently bugged me. Fortunately for me, while I was learning the Go programming language I stumbled across Hugo, a static site generator written in this language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch - Wind Power</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/scratch/</guid>
      <description>Projects &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Scratch - Wind Power
 As part of the popular Harvard University course CS50x that I took through EdX, I built a small Scratch application in completing the first problem set.
 Scratch is a &amp;lsquo;language&amp;rsquo; wherein you create programs by dragging together and connecting “blocks”. Unlike other programming languages, Scratch is very visual, making it a good first project for building fundamentals and learning to think like a programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/about/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ndash; Senior data engineer building performant pipelines and data ecosystems that empower data-driven organizations through self-service analytics. Based in the Boston, MA, USA area.
  I&amp;rsquo;m currently a senior data engineer at Interfolio.
 Interfolio offers consumer/enterprise faculty information SaaS products in serving the global higher education market. I’m building a modern business intelligence stack from the ground up in a way that allows both internal and external end users to answer important questions through supported self-service analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/books/</guid>
      <description>Countdown: Our Last, Best Hope for a Future on Earth? &amp;middot;  by Alan Weisman &amp;middot;  IN PROGRESS   Know My Name &amp;middot;  by Chanel Miller &amp;middot;  Mar 2021   Ready Player Two &amp;middot;  by Ernest Cline &amp;middot;  Jan 2021   The Simple Path to Wealth: Your Road Map to Financial Independence and a Rich, Free Life &amp;middot;  by J L Collins &amp;middot;  Aug 2020   Lab Rats: How Silicon Valley Made Work Miserable for the Rest of Us &amp;middot;  by Dan Lyons &amp;middot;  Jul 2020   How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big &amp;middot;  by Scott Adams &amp;middot;  May 2020   Enlightenment Now &amp;middot;  by Steven Pinker &amp;middot;  Jun 2019   Bullshit Jobs: A Theory &amp;middot;  by David Graeber &amp;middot;  Jan 2019   A Mother&#39;s Reckoning &amp;middot;  by Sue Klebold &amp;middot;  Jun 2018   Columbine &amp;middot;  by Dave Cullen &amp;middot;  May 2018   The Complete Software Developer&#39;s Career Guide &amp;middot;  by John Sonmez &amp;middot;  Feb 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirect</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/lim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/lim/</guid>
      <description>window.location = &#34;https://andrewrgoss.com&#34;; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>There are tons of great resources all over the internet. I&#39;ve bookmarked hundreds of URLs and this page is my categorized collection of the references and free tools I&#39;ve found to be helpful. If you&#39;re reading this and have something to add or find a dead link please send me a note. I&#39;m continuing to add to this over time.
 API Services | Career Management | Cloud Computing | Computer Science | Data Engineering | DataOps | Data Science | Datasets | Data Visualization | Programming | Software Development | Web Applications | Website Tools</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>For more on my professional background including additional details around my work history, you can visit my LinkedIn profile.
  Summary Senior data engineer working to advance data-driven cultures by integrating disparate data sources and empowering end users to uncover key insights that tell a bigger story. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as both a developer and a technical consultant in leveraging people, process, and technology to tell stories using data across a variety of industries, while also building out numerous in-house platforms and systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/search/</guid>
      <description>Some ad/tracker blockers like Ghostery block Google Custom Search Engine. Allow Google AJAX Search API to show your search results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/travel/</guid>
      <description>Outside of work, I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about traveling the world, having new experiences, and broadening my perspective. I have a long, ambitious list of places that I want to try and visit in my lifetime, so I decided to start tracking where I&amp;rsquo;ve been and where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go in the future.
The places I&amp;rsquo;ve listed out below are grouped by geographical belonging, not cultural significance (for example, Russia being listed under Asia and not Europe).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>