<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Engineering on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer in Boston</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Engineering on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer in Boston</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GCP Professional Data Engineer Certification</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/gcp-professional-data-engineer-certification/</guid>
      <description>I am in the process of obtaining certification as a Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer. For exam prep, there are five recommended training courses to complete, which I am doing online through Coursera.
Training Courses  Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals&amp;middot; Course Certificate Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc on Google Cloud Platform&amp;middot; [IN PROGRESS] Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow on Google Cloud Platform Building Resilient Streaming Systems on Google Cloud Platform  About the Specialization This series of courses (created by Google Cloud) provides participants a hands-on introduction to designing and building data processing systems on Google Cloud Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/getting-started-with-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/getting-started-with-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>written by Richard Taylor

This is an excellent overview article that covers essential knowledge areas related to data engineering. Specifically the author digs into the following topics:
 A brief history of the big data sector and why it exists.
 What is big data? Terminology guide  What a data engineer is and how and why the role came to be.
 What is a data engineer? Fundamentals and ongoing trends Roles and responsibilities as a data engineer  Big picture overview of the technologies data engineers have been using thus far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Engineers vs. Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>The two positions are not interchangeable—and misperceptions of their roles can hurt teams and compromise productivity.
 written by Jesse Anderson
View original article

It’s important to understand the differences between a data engineer and a data scientist. Misunderstanding or not knowing these differences are making teams fail or underperform with big data.
A key misunderstanding is the strengths and weaknesses of each position. I think some of these misconceptions come from the diagrams that are used to describe data scientists and data engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps- Next Gen Data Engineering Organization</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</guid>
      <description>Large enterprises are experiencing a foundational shift in how they view their data and structure their data engineering teams. As organizations capture more data than ever before, and store it in an ever-increasing variety of data stores, the prospect of competing on analytics becomes more tantalizing than ever.
  written by Andy Palmer
View original article

The challenges of using data at scale, however, is rooted in the &amp;ldquo;data debt&amp;rdquo; accumulated over time by enterprises struggling to manage the extreme volume and variety of their data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why 2018 Will Be The Year Of The Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-the-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-the-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Alex Woodie, Managing Editor of Datanami
The shortage of data scientists - those triple-threat types who possess advanced statistics, business, and coding skills - has been well-documented over the years. But increasingly, businesses are facing a shortage of another key individual on the big data team who&amp;rsquo;s critical to achieving success - the data engineer.
 Data engineers are tasked with building and maintaining the pipes that serve up fresh and accurate data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/becoming-a-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/becoming-a-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Sergio Sola (with some grammatical edits by me)
Becoming a Data Engineer I am a software engineer working at HelloFresh. I have been with the company for five years so far. Before HelloFresh and in this company I had different roles.
I started my career as a web developer doing everything, something that nowadays is called &amp;lsquo;full stack developer&amp;rsquo; (I have a firm opinion about that position, and it is not good, but that would be another article).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Productive Data Engineering Team?</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/what-is-a-productive-data-engineering-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/what-is-a-productive-data-engineering-team/</guid>
      <description>written by Jesse Anderson
 Merging the gaps between data science and engineering, and what each side can learn from the other.
 In my experience working with data engineering teams, I find that most teams don’t realize they have to change their thinking about data and systems to be successful with big data. Data engineering teams need to think about how data is valuable and at what scale the data is coming in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Data Engineer</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-rise-of-the-data-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-rise-of-the-data-engineer/</guid>
      <description>written by Maxime Beauchemin
I joined Facebook in 2011 as a business intelligence engineer. By the time I left in 2013, I was a data engineer.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t promoted or assigned to this new role. Instead, Facebook came to realize that the work we were doing transcended classic business intelligence. The role we&amp;rsquo;d created for ourselves was a new discipline entirely.
My team was at forefront of this transformation. We were developing new skills, new ways of doing things, new tools, and&amp;ndash;more often than not&amp;ndash;turning our backs to traditional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need Both Data Scientists &amp; Data Engineers</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</guid>
      <description>written by Neeraj Chadha
When it comes to the medical profession, doctors get all the glory. In the world of IoT, it&amp;rsquo;s data scientists who get most of the attention and acclaim. They extract critical intelligence from big data so businesses can make informed decisions on the spot. But they don&amp;rsquo;t do their work in a vacuum. Data scientists can&amp;rsquo;t dazzle their industries without data engineers. These unheralded champions, equivalent to nurses, ensure that big data keeps flowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Science Industry: Who Does What</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</guid>
      <description>Great infographic from DataCamp that lays out the roles and skills associated with a data science team. As a data engineer within this group, these are the kind of people I work with day-to-day. *Source: DataCamp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Data Engineers &amp; Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/comparing-data-engineers--data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/comparing-data-engineers--data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Data engineer and data scientist are the two most popular career tracks in big data - but how do they compare? At a high level, data engineers are concerned with data infrastructure, while data scientists are concerned with analysis.
Like data scientists, data engineers write code. They’re highly analytical, and are interested in data visualization. Unlike data scientists — and inspired by a more mature parent, software engineering — data engineers build tools, infrastructure, frameworks, and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report- The State of Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/report--the-state-of-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an excellent report by Stitch on the state of data engineering.
Today, there are 6,500 people on LinkedIn who call themselves data engineers. In San Francisco alone, there are 6,600 job listings for this same title. The number of data engineers has doubled in the past year, but engineering leaders still find themselves faced with a significant shortage of data engineering talent.
The need for data talent is born from a fundamental shift: tech companies are now data companies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>