<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys With PuTTY and Cygwin for Windows</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-keys-with-putty-and-cygwin-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>In my work at Digitas, I need to login to a number of client-specific Linux machines via a terminal emulator (there is no UI for these remote environments) from my local Windows laptop. For this my team uses Cygwin, a Linux-like environment for Windows making it possible to port software running on POSIX systems (such as Linux, BSD, and Unix systems) to Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to login of course just using a standard username/password combination with Mosh or SSH at the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH With Git Bash and TortoiseGit for Windows</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2016/ssh-with-git-bash-and-tortoisegit-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever written code of any kind for professional and personal purposes, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely come across the concept of Source Control Management (SCM). When I first became a developer, I used Subversion as my SCM tool but have since switched to the more popular Git. I use git to commit the latest versions of code in both Linux and Windows environments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on Windows in this post as this is the operating system for my personal computer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>