<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data on Andrew Goss · Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/big-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big Data on Andrew Goss · Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS &amp; Snowflake vs GCP</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/aws--snowflake-vs-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/aws--snowflake-vs-gcp/</guid>
      <description>written by Stefano Solimito 
When we talk about data, the number of technologies available on the market is overwhelming and staying up to date is a key challenge both for businesses and for engineers.
With this article, Stefano Solimito shares the joys and pains of the learning journey of building a new data platform using some of the most cutting edge technologies available — AWS (Amazon Web Services), Snowflake and Looker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</guid>
      <description>COMPLETION CERTIFICATE
COURSE MATERIALS

Description  Learn the concepts of Spark&amp;rsquo;s Resilient Distributed Datastores Get a crash course in the Scala programming language Develop and run Spark jobs quickly using Scala Translate complex analysis problems into iterative or multi-stage Spark scripts Scale up to larger data sets using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Elastic MapReduce service Understand how Hadoop YARN distributes Spark across computing clusters Practice using other Spark technologies, like Spark SQL, DataFrames, DataSets, Spark Streaming, and GraphX  What I got from this course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Similar Movies from One Million Ratings on EMR</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/mov_sim_ml_1m_emr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/mov_sim_ml_1m_emr/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Creating Similar Movies from One Million Ratings on EMR

I completed an exercise of compiling a .jar file from my Scala code through IntelliJ IDEA, uploading this to a S3 bucket I created, and then running a Spark job on a AWS EMR cluster that I spun up. Here are the steps I took with screenshots, since I terminated my EMR cluster at the end to avoid incurring unnecessary costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 Big Data Landscape</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-2017-big-data-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/the-2017-big-data-landscape/</guid>
      <description>Just released - an excellent &amp;ldquo;State of the Union&amp;rdquo; roundup of the key trends in the 2017 data ecosystem. Some high level trends and questions that are explored in this comprehensive article:
 Big data + AI = the new stack. Big data provides the pipes, and AI provides the smarts. Enterprise budgets - follow the money Enterprise data moving to the cloud As the big data landscape gets busier every passing year, is big data consolidation coming?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data University- Hadoop 101</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/big-data-university--hadoop-101/</guid>
      <description>Course Code: BD0111EN
Course Certificate
Course Link
IBM Analytics Demo Cloud
Lesson Transcripts/Labs  My goal in taking this course was to expand upon my knowledge around Apache Hadoop, a free, open source, Java-based programming framework. Topics in this course include:
 Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s architecture and core components, such as MapReduce and the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS). Adding/removing nodes from Hadoop clusters, how to check available disk space on each node, and how to modify configuration parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>