<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Data Engineer | Technical Consultant | Business Intelligence Developer - Andrew Goss</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Data Engineer | Technical Consultant | Business Intelligence Developer - Andrew Goss</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marketing and Technology Portmanteau</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/the-marketing-and-technology-portmanteau/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/the-marketing-and-technology-portmanteau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering, what on earth is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portmanteau&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;portmanteau&lt;/a&gt;? Never heard that term before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing technology is not just about making existing processes more efficient. It’s the interface by which marketing sees and touches the digital world. Your choice of marketing software — and how you use it — will shape the experiences you deliver to prospects and customers. (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/2014/01/strategy-marketing-technology-intertwined/&#34;&gt;http://chiefmartec.com/2014/01/strategy-marketing-technology-intertwined/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, I came across several brilliant articles written by &lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scott Brinker&lt;/a&gt; and really bought into his thought leadership on the convergence of these fields. I highly recommend the following reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/2010/04/rise-of-the-marketing-technologist&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Rise of the Marketing Technologist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/2011/01/8-things-every-marketing-technologist-should-know&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8 Things Every Marketing Technologist Should Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/2012/05/engineers-are-becoming-a-lot-like-marketers-too&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Engineers Are Becoming a Lot Like Marketers Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefmartec.com/2013/12/marketing-technologist-neo-marketing-matrix&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Marketing Technologist: Neo of the Marketing Matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brinker&amp;rsquo;s overarching vision is that the cross-pollination of marketing and technology cultures will lead to innovative hybrid models of marketing technology management that are indigenous to a new era of marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computational marketing can leverage the tsunami of big data with real-time experimentation, optimization, and personalization — intertwined with human marketing expertise and judgment — to transform this industry over the next 10 years. homogeneous mixture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the economies of cloud computing, these computational marketing capabilities will not be limited to a handful of the Fortune 500. Marketers of any size will be able to utilize them — if they know how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portrait of a Chief Marketing Technologist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A business/technology hybrid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong engineering, IT skill set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early adopter &amp;amp; pragmatist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lives &amp;amp; breathes marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Evaluation Links</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/website-evaluation-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/website-evaluation-links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot you can learn about a website by simply having the URL address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;builtwith:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://builtwith.com&#34;&gt;http://builtwith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-design-resizer:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Google Design: Resizer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interactive viewer to see and test how digital products respond to material design breakpoints across desktop, mobile, and tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://design.google.com/resizer&#34;&gt;http://design.google.com/resizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://design.google.com/articles/introducing-resizer&#34;&gt;https://design.google.com/articles/introducing-resizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-grader:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Website Grader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://website.grader.com&#34;&gt;https://website.grader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-hosting-this:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Who Is Hosting This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--![WhoIsHostingThis.com](http://media.whoishostingthis.com/2/v98/images/wiht-logo.png)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I looked at websites owned by either companies or individuals and wondered who the web hosting provider was; who was responsible for powering the website? No more. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whoishostingthis.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WhoIsHostingThis&lt;/a&gt; allows a user to simply enter the domain name of any site and instantly uncover the identity of the company that is hosting the site. For example, I follow a web developer at HubSpot on Twitter by the name of Jonathan Kim. I&amp;rsquo;ve read his personal blog several times and wondered who he chose for his provider. After all, he is a developer at a marketing company and so I figured he might be interested in a hosting company that could provide advanced analytics as part of their package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out my hunches were at least partially right. WhoIsHostingThis.com showed me that Kim is powering his personal blog by a web hosting company called CloudFlare. While there was not a review particular for this particular provider, it drove me to visit the website of this hosting company that I was not previously familiar with. Although CloudFlare does provide insight into website traffic, its biggest draw seems to be that it is designed to be a community for webmasters. It protects and accelerates websites by blocking threats and limiting bots and crawlers from wasting bandwidth and server resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using WhoIsHostingThis.com has given me useful insight about web hosting that should prove valuable to me when it comes time to selecting a web hosting provider for my own personal website. Also of note, the IP address is displayed. There are lots of IP address services across the web that allow a user to pinpoint the location of the server that is powering any given website. In this case, CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s servers are located at the company&amp;rsquo;s headquarters in San Francisco. I may explore IP addresses a bit further in a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-theme-detector:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Wordpress Theme Detector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&#34;&gt;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.github.io/img/post/hugo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve believed in the importance of having a blog but have struggled to keep one going. I started out using Blogger back in the day and most recently was using Wordpress. But there were features about these blogging platforms that consistently bugged me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I prepared a post with the text and articles I would have to publish it to see how it looks within the context of the overall site. Yes- it&amp;rsquo;s true that you can save content in draft mode and only make it live after proof-reading. But this was in a different screen - the admin section. I much prefer to see a live preview as I work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that some of my more technical posts needed to contain code snippets but Wordpress is too-friendly for this working in a WYSIWYG editor. Simply copying and pasting this code within a post didn&amp;rsquo;t work as it removed all of the syntax highlighting and formatting from my favorite IDE (interactive development environment) tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Wordpress it was the setup was easy enough using a one-click install from a hosting dashboard (BlueHost in my case) and then being able to install plugins, themes, and updates, all from the Wordpress admin. But I had to login through that dashboard every time to access my Wordpress site. On top of that, I was paying a small monthly cost for this hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my site rendered very slowly with Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-a-static-site-generator:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Hugo: A Static Site Generator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo solves these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m already a fan and user of the Go language, and so in following a number of the Go social communities, I discovered Hugo. A static site generator is an application that can take content in some original description (markdown in the case of Hugo), and renders final content by applying rules. This final content can then be hosted anywhere, without the need for server-side runtime support, such as Python/PHP/Go/Node/etc, because it does not require server-side processing to handle rendering the pages on the fly. This makes the site very portable and simple to deploy, and can be served out of aggressive caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never used Jekyll personally, but I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it. A few other static site generators &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;have sprung up&lt;/a&gt; since Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one that caught my attention was &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. It has all the goodness from Jekyll, but it&amp;rsquo;s way easier to setup. Hugo itself is written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, but they build &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;executable binaries&lt;/a&gt; for a lot of platforms and architectures. So you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install anything else. Even compiling it yourself isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of creating a new website is very similar to Jekyll. The &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command literally explains itself (&lt;code&gt;hugo help&lt;/code&gt;) and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on its website should suffice for most users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully migrated my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/samueldebruyn.github.io/tree/5f5719a9d4519f8fbd4cdfffa2a10b3f066401ef&#34;&gt;Jekyll blog&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/sa.muel.be-hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and haven&amp;rsquo;t regretted it ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major disadvantages of Hugo, or any static site generator for that matter, is integrating &lt;strong&gt;search&lt;/strong&gt;. You need some &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-are-you-implementing-site-search/986/14&#34;&gt;JavaScript magic&lt;/a&gt; or a 3rd party search provider like &lt;a href=&#34;https://cse.google.com&#34;&gt;Google Custom Search Engine&lt;/a&gt; (which I went for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other dynamic part of an ordinary blog is &lt;strong&gt;the comment section&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, the easiest way to &lt;em&gt;fix&lt;/em&gt; this is relying on a 3rd party comments plugin like &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, these two disadvantages are easily outweighed by the advantages of a static website. Your website will survive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot_effect&#34;&gt;slashdotting&lt;/a&gt; and the only required maintenance is literally making sure your web server stays online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>