<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Andrewrgoss.com</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Andrewrgoss.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Evaluation Links</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/website-evaluation-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/website-evaluation-links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot you can learn about a website by simply having the URL address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;builtwith:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://builtwith.com&#34;&gt;http://builtwith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-design-resizer:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Google Design: Resizer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interactive viewer to see and test how digital products respond to material design breakpoints across desktop, mobile, and tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://design.google.com/resizer&#34;&gt;http://design.google.com/resizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://design.google.com/articles/introducing-resizer&#34;&gt;https://design.google.com/articles/introducing-resizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-grader:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Website Grader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://website.grader.com&#34;&gt;https://website.grader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-hosting-this:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Who Is Hosting This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--![WhoIsHostingThis.com](http://media.whoishostingthis.com/2/v98/images/wiht-logo.png)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I looked at websites owned by either companies or individuals and wondered who the web hosting provider was; who was responsible for powering the website? No more. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whoishostingthis.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WhoIsHostingThis&lt;/a&gt; allows a user to simply enter the domain name of any site and instantly uncover the identity of the company that is hosting the site. For example, I follow a web developer at HubSpot on Twitter by the name of Jonathan Kim. I&amp;rsquo;ve read his personal blog several times and wondered who he chose for his provider. After all, he is a developer at a marketing company and so I figured he might be interested in a hosting company that could provide advanced analytics as part of their package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out my hunches were at least partially right. WhoIsHostingThis.com showed me that Kim is powering his personal blog by a web hosting company called CloudFlare. While there was not a review particular for this particular provider, it drove me to visit the website of this hosting company that I was not previously familiar with. Although CloudFlare does provide insight into website traffic, its biggest draw seems to be that it is designed to be a community for webmasters. It protects and accelerates websites by blocking threats and limiting bots and crawlers from wasting bandwidth and server resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using WhoIsHostingThis.com has given me useful insight about web hosting that should prove valuable to me when it comes time to selecting a web hosting provider for my own personal website. Also of note, the IP address is displayed. There are lots of IP address services across the web that allow a user to pinpoint the location of the server that is powering any given website. In this case, CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s servers are located at the company&amp;rsquo;s headquarters in San Francisco. I may explore IP addresses a bit further in a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-theme-detector:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Wordpress Theme Detector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&#34;&gt;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Why I made the switch from Wordpress to Hugo…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-good-blogging-platform:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;A good blogging platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes a good blogging platform really good? Well, that depends on the blogger. Programmers would need different features than make-up bloggers. As a programmer, I need to be able to easily integrate pieces of code with syntax highlighting in my posts and I&amp;rsquo;d prefer writing them in my favorite text/code editor instead of in a WYSIWYG editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started out using this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never used Jekyll personally, but I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it. A few other static site generators &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;have sprung up&lt;/a&gt; since Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one that caught my attention was &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. It has all the goodness from Jekyll, but it&amp;rsquo;s way easier to setup. Hugo itself is written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, but they build &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;executable binaries&lt;/a&gt; for a lot of platforms and architectures. So you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install anything else. Even compiling it yourself isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of creating a new website is very similar to Jekyll. The &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command literally explains itself (&lt;code&gt;hugo help&lt;/code&gt;) and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on its website should suffice for most users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully migrated my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/samueldebruyn.github.io/tree/5f5719a9d4519f8fbd4cdfffa2a10b3f066401ef&#34;&gt;Jekyll blog&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SamuelDebruyn/sa.muel.be-hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and haven&amp;rsquo;t regretted it ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages:f3941651fa35be8fa9dd1215cdae54e4&#34;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major disadvantages of Hugo, or any static site generator for that matter, is integrating &lt;strong&gt;search&lt;/strong&gt;. You need some &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io/t/how-are-you-implementing-site-search/986/14&#34;&gt;JavaScript magic&lt;/a&gt; or a 3rd party search provider like &lt;a href=&#34;https://cse.google.com&#34;&gt;Google Custom Search Engine&lt;/a&gt; (which I went for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other dynamic part of an ordinary blog is &lt;strong&gt;the comment section&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, the easiest way to &lt;em&gt;fix&lt;/em&gt; this is relying on a 3rd party comments plugin like &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, these two disadvantages are easily outweighed by the advantages of a static website. Your website will survive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot_effect&#34;&gt;slashdotting&lt;/a&gt; and the only required maintenance is literally making sure your web server stays online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Travel Pics From Each Country</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2015/favorite-travel-pics-from-each-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2015/favorite-travel-pics-from-each-country/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My favorite travel pictures from each country I&amp;rsquo;ve visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;peru:f120e07de792c8e26ccd0b69913a5c3d&#34;&gt;Peru&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;israel:f120e07de792c8e26ccd0b69913a5c3d&#34;&gt;Israel&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>