<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrewrgoss.com</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrewrgoss.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Andrew Goss.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Evaluation Links</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/02/11/website-evaluation-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/02/11/website-evaluation-links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot you can learn about a website by simply having the URL address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;builtwith:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://builtwith.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://builtwith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-grader:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Website Grader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://website.grader.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://website.grader.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-hosting-this:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Who Is Hosting This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--![WhoIsHostingThis.com](http://media.whoishostingthis.com/2/v98/images/wiht-logo.png)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I looked at websites owned by either companies or individuals and wondered who the web hosting provider was; who was responsible for powering the website? No more. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whoishostingthis.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WhoIsHostingThis&lt;/a&gt; allows a user to simply enter the domain name of any site and instantly uncover the identity of the company that is hosting the site. For example, I follow a web developer at HubSpot on Twitter by the name of Jonathan Kim. I&amp;rsquo;ve read his personal blog several times and wondered who he chose for his provider. After all, he is a developer at a marketing company and so I figured he might be interested in a hosting company that could provide advanced analytics as part of their package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out my hunches were at least partially right. WhoIsHostingThis.com showed me that Kim is powering his personal blog by a web hosting company called CloudFlare. While there was not a review particular for this particular provider, it drove me to visit the website of this hosting company that I was not previously familiar with. Although CloudFlare does provide insight into website traffic, its biggest draw seems to be that it is designed to be a community for webmasters. It protects and accelerates websites by blocking threats and limiting bots and crawlers from wasting bandwidth and server resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using WhoIsHostingThis.com has given me useful insight about web hosting that should prove valuable to me when it comes time to selecting a web hosting provider for my own personal website. Also of note, the IP address is displayed. There are lots of IP address services across the web that allow a user to pinpoint the location of the server that is powering any given website. In this case, CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s servers are located at the company&amp;rsquo;s headquarters in San Francisco. I may explore IP addresses a bit further in a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-theme-detector:4bad1ad5850f28d82da8c8c5ec807869&#34;&gt;Wordpress Theme Detector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.wpthemedetector.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Switched to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/01/26/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.github.io/2016/01/26/why-i-switched-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why I made the switch from Wordpress to Hugo…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>