<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Data Engineer | Tech Consultant | BI Developer in Boston</title>
    <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Data Engineer | Tech Consultant | BI Developer in Boston</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need Both Data Scientists &amp; Data Engineers</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2017/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2017/we-need-both-data-scientists--data-engineers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;written by Neeraj Chadha&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the medical profession, doctors get all the glory. In the world of IoT, it&amp;rsquo;s data scientists who get most of the attention and acclaim. They extract critical intelligence from big data so businesses can make informed decisions on the spot. But they don&amp;rsquo;t do their work in a vacuum. Data scientists can&amp;rsquo;t dazzle their industries without data engineers. These unheralded champions, equivalent to nurses, ensure that big data keeps flowing. As anyone who works in the medical profession will tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s the nurses who keep the hospital running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What exactly do data engineers do? They work behind the scenes to design and maintain the networks and software that keep the big data pipeline operating. Like a hospital&amp;rsquo;s nursing staff, data engineers set the stage and keep it running. The roles of data scientists and data engineers can be confusing because they have some overlap. Data engineer and data scientist are not different titles for the same job, however. The two jobs require different skills and experience. Some data scientists can do data engineering. Some data engineers can do data analysis and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roles do have distinctions, however. For instance, large applications call for the skills of data engineers. Research is a primary focus of the data scientist. Like nurses, data engineers are a special breed. The best have certain personality traits that help them excel: focus, mechanical aptitude, patience and persistence. Good data engineers get down in the trenches. They want to understand how and why data pipelines work&amp;ndash;or don&amp;rsquo;t work. Data engineers need patience and persistence to set things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do modeling, data scientists need data engineers to gather, store and process data so they can analyze it for insights. Responsible for data management, data engineers handle procedures, guidelines and standards. They develop data-management technologies and software-engineering tools. They design custom software and discover ways to recover from disasters. They improve data reliability, efficiency and quality. User-defined functions and analytics are part of a data engineer&amp;rsquo;s job, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, data scientists take a big-picture view of things and have a less nuts-and-bolts relationship with data. They handle analytic projects that arise from the needs of the business. Data scientists also take on data-mining architectures, modeling standards, reporting and data methodologies. They manage data-mining-system performance and efficiency, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because they build and maintain the data pipelines that send information to data scientists, the work of data engineers is very valuable. They can run basic learning models if they understand algorithms. But data scientists tackle business problems that take sophisticated machine-learning algorithms. The best data scientists adapt machine-learning models to meet the changing requirements of the business or agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tools-for-tough-big-data-challenges:029588ea80b351abbdc001504769805c&#34;&gt;Tools for Tough Big Data Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges of database integration and unstructured big data are handled by the data engineers. They must clean up that unstructured data before they pass it to anyone in the organization who needs it. Like nurses who prep patients for surgery, data engineers prepare the foundation for data scientists to work easily with data. They should know data warehousing, database design, data collection and transfer, and coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part of the data pipeline on which data engineers are focusing on determines which tools they will use. Data engineers at the rear of the pipeline build APIs for data consumption, integrate data sets from external sources and analyze how the data is used to support business growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although these professionals have many languages to choose from, Python is a good option. Data engineers use it to write code related to data ingestion. Python can talk to any data store, such as NoSQL and RDBMS. Data engineers may have to use big data technologies such as Hadoop and Spark to suggest improvements on the basis of how data is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data engineers have many tools at their disposal, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NoSQL databases (e.g., Cassandra and MongoDB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop and related tools such as HBase, Hive and Pig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pentaho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VMware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-scientists-and-data-engineers-growth-on-the-horizon:029588ea80b351abbdc001504769805c&#34;&gt;Data Scientists and Data Engineers: Growth on the Horizon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study last year from the Economist Intelligence Unit surveyed 422 executives in the U.S. and Europe. The survey asked them about the digital skills most in demand among industries such as financial services, health care, manufacturing and retail. Forty-three percent of the executives said that in three years, analytics and big data skills will be the most important digital capabilities at their companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As life and business become increasingly data driven, demand for both data engineers and data scientists will continue to rise. Now is the time for data professionals to acquire or build on their skills so they will be well positioned for career advancement and job security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datacenterjournal.com/need-data-scientists-data-engineers&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datacenterjournal.com&#34; target=_&gt;Data Center Journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Engineers vs. Data Scientists</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2017/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2017/data-engineers-vs.-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data engineer and data scientist are the two most popular career tracks in big data - but how do they compare? At a high level, data engineers are concerned with data infrastructure, while data scientists are concerned with analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like data scientists, data engineers write code. They’re highly analytical, and are interested in data visualization.
Unlike data scientists — and inspired by a more mature parent, software engineering — data engineers build tools, infrastructure, frameworks, and services. In fact, it’s arguable that data engineering is much closer to software engineering than it is to data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitchdata.com&#34; target=_&gt;Stitch&lt;/a&gt; digs into LinkedIn data to analyze the skills associated with each role. It also provides links to other helpful resources for further perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*QOw6_pX9r1G_ua_n0DsICQ.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.stitchdata.com/data-engineer-vs-data-scientist-the-difference-according-to-linkedin-e0bee6248fd4&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Sources: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitchdata.com&#34; target=_&gt;Stitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com&#34; target=_&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Science Industry: Who Does What</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/the-data-science-industry-who-does-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great infographic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt; that lays out the roles and skills associated with a data science team. As a data engineer within this group, these are the kind of people I work with day-to-day.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://101.datascience.community/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/datasciencejobs.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacamp.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stages of the Analytics Life Cycle</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/stages-of-the-analytics-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Across industries, the applied use of data to inform business decisions has become a foundational (arguably critical) element of business. The end goal is to ultimately derive actionable insights from vast amounts of data being collected but it takes a series of activities/tasks to arrive at this juncture. Here is a description of each stage of the analytics life cycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Acquisition&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve scraping data, interfacing with APIs, querying relational and non-relational databases, or defining strategy in relation to what data to pursue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Cleaning/Transformation&lt;/b&gt; – This may involve parsing and aggregating messy, incomplete, and unstructured data sources to produce datasets that can be used in analytics and/or predictive modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Analytics&lt;/b&gt; – This involves statistical and machine learning-based modeling in order to understand, describe, or predict patterns in the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prescribing Actions&lt;/b&gt; – This involves interpreting analytical results through the lens of business priorities, and using data-driven insights to inform strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Programming/Automation&lt;/b&gt; – In many cases, data scientists are responsible for creating libraries and utilities to operationalize or simplify various stages of this process. Often, they will contribute production-level code for a firm’s data products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: Burtch Works&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-data-analytics-lifecycle:fabfcdc15793a32766e038f5387cbc68&#34;&gt;Big Data Analytics Lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Data analysis differs from traditional data analysis primarily due to the volume, velocity, and variety of characteristics for the data being processed. This is a helpful overview I found on the high-level steps involved with acquiring, processing, analyzing, and repurposing data with the end goal of performing Big Data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.informit.com/content/images/chap3_9780134291079/elementLinks/03fig06.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=2473128&amp;seqNum=11&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;InformIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Science Conference East</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/open-data-science-conference-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com/boston&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andrewrgoss.com/img/post/odsc.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; title=&#34;Open Data Science Conference&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2016 I attended my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.odsc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Data Science Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Boston. There were some 3,000+ data science practioners that came together at the Boston Convention &amp;amp; Exhibition Center to share ideas about this rapidly changing discipline. The following topics were covered throughout the conference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hadoop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended sessions on popular data science statistical models and using Python for data science, where we worked through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brianbelljr/fantasy_football/blob/master/football.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop materials from the conference are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opendatascience.com/category/conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;opendatascience.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Disciplines Compared to Data Science</title>
      <link>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>http://andrewrgoss.com/2016/analytic-disciplines-compared-to-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came across an excellent article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt; that digs into the differences between data science, data mining, machine learning, statistics, operations research, and so on. The author compares several analytic disciplines that overlap to explain the differences and common denominators. Typical job titles, types of analyses, and industries traditionally attached to each discipline are also detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;*Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/17-analytic-disciplines-compared&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>