<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elt on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/elt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elt on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/elt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Cleaning and How Do You Do It?</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/what-is-data-cleaning-and-how-do-you-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/what-is-data-cleaning-and-how-do-you-do-it/</guid>
      <description>written by Bash Sarmiento 
The world we live in is now largely dependent on data. Fields and industries ranging from finance, education, healthcare, and even entertainment all rely on data to streamline processes and maintain the required transmissions without losing data quality and security.
To make sure that every piece of data remains correct, usable, and consistent across your entire network, a process called data cleaning is necessary. To learn more about this emerging best practice in data management and how to do it, here is everything you need to know about data cleaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Stack - Open-Source Edition</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/modern-data-stack---open-source-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/modern-data-stack---open-source-edition/</guid>
      <description>written by Gleb Mezhanskiy
 Open source is not by itself a compelling enough reason to choose a technology for the data stack, but it can be the most feasible solution in some situations, for example, in a highly regulated industry or due to local privacy and data security legislation that may prohibit the use of foreign SaaS vendors.
 The author of this post previously proposed a data stack for a typical analytical use case along with the key criteria to choose tech for each step in the data pipeline, such as minimal operational overhead, scalability, and pricing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELT Data Pipelining in Snowflake Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/elt-data-pipelining-in-snowflake-data-warehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/elt-data-pipelining-in-snowflake-data-warehouse/</guid>
      <description>written by Christopher Tao 
In my previous post:
Building Snowpipe on Azure Blob Storage Using Azure Portal Web UI for Snowflake Data Warehouse
Snowpipe was introduced to be utilized for automatically discovering new data files in cloud storage (e.g. Azure Blob Storage) and then load the data into a certain table.
Snowpipe is a very convenient tool for the above purposes. However, Snowpipe itself is only considered as the “E” (Extract) of ELT, because only COPY INTO command is allowed in a Snowpipe creating statement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>