<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Data Stack Conference</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/open-source-data-stack-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/open-source-data-stack-conference/</guid>
      <description>In September 2021 I attended an excellent virtual conference, the Open Source Data Stack Conference. The conference profiled a number of platforms that can be combined together to form a modern open source data stack.
The emergence of the modern data stack has seen a rapid spike in the number of data tools an organization can use to drive better decision making. Each tool has become highly specialized in its portion of the data lifecycle, plus tools that are open source are a powerful way for technology buyers to reduce exposure to vendor lock-in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Stack - Open-Source Edition</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/modern-data-stack---open-source-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/modern-data-stack---open-source-edition/</guid>
      <description>written by Gleb Mezhanskiy
 Open source is not by itself a compelling enough reason to choose a technology for the data stack, but it can be the most feasible solution in some situations, for example, in a highly regulated industry or due to local privacy and data security legislation that may prohibit the use of foreign SaaS vendors.
 The author of this post previously proposed a data stack for a typical analytical use case along with the key criteria to choose tech for each step in the data pipeline, such as minimal operational overhead, scalability, and pricing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>