<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scala on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer in Boston</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/scala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scala on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer in Boston</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/scala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Streaming with Spark and Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/twitter_streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/projects/twitter_streaming/</guid>
      <description>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Twitter Streaming

Go to: DataChatter
PopularHashtags.scala This is a Spark streaming script that monitors live tweets from Twitter and keeps track of the 10 most popular hashtags as tweets are received.
Each hashtag is mapped to a key/value pair of (hashtag, 1) so they can be counted up over a 5-minute sliding window with this line of code:
val hashtagCounts = hashtagKeyValues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udemy- Apache Spark 2.0 With Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/udemy--apache-spark-2.0-with-scala/</guid>
      <description>COURSE LINK
COURSE MATERIALS

Description  Learn the concepts of Spark&amp;rsquo;s Resilient Distributed Datastores Get a crash course in the Scala programming language Develop and run Spark jobs quickly using Scala Translate complex analysis problems into iterative or multi-stage Spark scripts Scale up to larger data sets using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Elastic MapReduce service Understand how Hadoop YARN distributes Spark across computing clusters Practice using other Spark technologies, like Spark SQL, DataFrames, DataSets, Spark Streaming, and GraphX  What am I got from this course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Path to Learning Scala</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/my-path-to-learning-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/my-path-to-learning-scala/</guid>
      <description>I recently joined a new data engineering team at DigitasLBi and Scala is the predominant language being used. Having never coded in this language, I sought to quickly learn it and wanted to share the numerous resources I came across and bookmarked.
The first place I usually turn when learning something new is to complete an introductory online course with videos and exercises. The most popular course for Scala is Functional Programming Principles in Scala on Coursera and it is taught by the inventor of the language (Martin Odersky), so I gave it a whirl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>