<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Infrastructure on Andrew Goss · Data Eng and Analytics Leader</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Infrastructure on Andrew Goss · Data Eng and Analytics Leader</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/data-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Right Tools For Your Data Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2022/choosing-the-right-tools-for-your-data-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2022/choosing-the-right-tools-for-your-data-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>written by Start Data Engineering
If you are building data pipelines from the ground up, the number of available data engineering tools to choose from can be overwhelming. If you are thinking:
 Most of the tools seem to be doing the same/similar thing, which one should I choose? How to choose the right tool for my data pipeline?
 Then this post is for you. In this post, Start Data Engineering goes over the core components of data pipelines and how you can use your requirements to select the right tools:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Architectures for Modern Data Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/emerging-architectures-for-modern-data-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2021/emerging-architectures-for-modern-data-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>*Source: Andreessen Horowitz  written by Matt Bornstein, Martin Casado, and Jennifer Li
As an industry, we’ve gotten exceptionally good at building large, complex software systems. We’re now starting to see the rise of massive, complex systems built around data – where the primary business value of the system comes from the analysis of data, rather than the software directly. We’re seeing quick-moving impacts of this trend across the industry, including the emergence of new roles, shifts in customer spending, and the emergence of new startups providing infrastructure and tooling around data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>