<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dataops on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/dataops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dataops on Andrew Goss · Senior Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/dataops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps is NOT Just DevOps for Data</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/dataops-is-not-just-devops-for-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2020/dataops-is-not-just-devops-for-data/</guid>
      <description>written by DataKitchen 
One common misconception about DataOps is that it is just DevOps applied to data analytics. While a little semantically misleading, the name “DataOps” has one positive attribute. It communicates that data analytics can achieve what software development attained with DevOps. That is to say, DataOps can yield an order of magnitude improvement in quality and cycle time when data teams utilize new tools and methodologies. The specific ways that DataOps achieves these gains reflect the unique people, processes and tools characteristic of data teams (versus software development teams using DevOps).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of SQL-Based Data Modeling and DataOps</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/the-rise-of-sql-based-data-modeling-and-dataops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/the-rise-of-sql-based-data-modeling-and-dataops/</guid>
      <description>written by Thanh Dinh 
The resurgence of SQL-based RDBMS If there is one analytics trend we can all agree on, it is that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a vast increase in the amount of business data collected in the past decade. A typical business today uses dozens if not hundreds of cloud-based, subscription-as-a-service software, for all sorts of purposes. Together with more traditional in-house enterprise software, the average business produces a mountain of data today, compared to just a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps Is Here To Stay</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/dataops-is-here-to-stay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2019/dataops-is-here-to-stay/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Stephen Dawson on Unsplash
written by Pedro Martinez 
What Is DataOps? DataOps is a discipline that has become a necessity in a market where the demand for access to data assets and data products is skyrocketing. The inability of data platform teams and data management platforms to keep pace with the demands placed on them by DevOps-enabled teams led to the development of DataOps.[i]
In a nutshell, DataOps brings together data scientists, analysts, developers, and operations to work on the entire product/service lifecycle, from the design stage to production support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps- Next Gen Data Engineering Organization</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>admin@andrewrgoss.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/dataops--next-gen-data-engineering-organization/</guid>
      <description>Large enterprises are experiencing a foundational shift in how they view their data and structure their data engineering teams. As organizations capture more data than ever before, and store it in an ever-increasing variety of data stores, the prospect of competing on analytics becomes more tantalizing than ever.
  written by Andy Palmer
View original article

The challenges of using data at scale, however, is rooted in the &amp;ldquo;data debt&amp;rdquo; accumulated over time by enterprises struggling to manage the extreme volume and variety of their data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>