<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Management on Andrew Goss · Data Engineer</title>
    <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/career-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career Management on Andrew Goss · Data Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewrgoss.com/tags/career-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Learn</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>As 2018 began, I spent some time thinking about my goals for this year. An area that I wanted to focus on is improving upon how I learn. Many have argued that the ability to learn is the most valuable skill you can possess throughout your career and working in the ever-changing field of technology, I certainly would not disagree.
So I decided to invest in the 10 Steps to Learn Anything Quickly course offered by Simple Programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Engineer Notes</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/effective-engineer-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2018/effective-engineer-notes/</guid>
      <description>Some great reference notes from a highly recommended &amp;#x1F44D; book for engineers looking to reach the next level in their careers.
 By Edmond Lau
theeffectiveengineer.com
What&amp;rsquo;s an Effective Engineer?  They are the people who get things done. Effective Engineers produce results.  Adopt the Right Mindsets Focus on High Leverage Activities  Leverage = Impact Produced / Time Invested Use Leverage as Your Yardstick for Effectiveness 80% of the impact comes from 20% of the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Start a Successful Side Project</title>
      <link>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/how-to-start-a-successful-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>andrewrgoss@gmail.com (Andrew Goss)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewrgoss.com/2017/how-to-start-a-successful-side-project/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on Simple Programmer.
written by Alexander Petkov
View original article

Do you ever feel like you are confident in only one particular field? Like you know only one tiny corner of the vast software universe? Then, the minute you try to escape it and work on something different, you get frustrated. And if you need to build a complete, functional project—from scratch—with:
Initial research and machine setup (packages, installments)Managing dependencies (libraries, build tools, automations)The whole business logic plus high test coverageProduction deployment … then somebody else has to do everything except the little corner of your comfort zone?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>